怦然心动
我最大的愿望就是朱莉·贝克能离我远点
All I ever wanted was for Juli Baker to leave me alone.
故事开始于1957年的夏天
It all began in the summer of 1957,
二年级开学的前夕
before the start of second grade.
我们到了
Here we are.
-你们觉得如何  -我喜欢这里
- What do you guys think? - I like this place.
-棒极了  -我的房间是什么颜色
- It's cool. - Uh, what color is my room?
别急嘛
Just you wait.
-我们进去瞧瞧  -等等  布莱斯
- Let's see what's inside. - Hey, come on, buddy Bryce.
你来帮我一起搬东西如何
Why don't, uh, you and I go help unload the van...
女士们可以去把厨房收拾好
...and the womenfolk here can get in the kitchen and start setting up.
好的  爸爸
Okay, Dad.
对我而言  这仅仅是我长达五年多的
For me, it was the beginning of what would be more than half a decade
躲避战和社交不适的开端
of strategic avoidance and social discomfort.
-你好  我是朱莉·贝克  -喂  你干什么呢
- Hi, I'm Juli Baker. - Hey, hey, what are you doing?
要帮忙吗
Don't you want some help?
不用  里面有贵重东西
No. There's some valuable things in there.
-那搬这个呢  -不不不  别动
- How about this one? - No, no, no.
快回家吧  你妈妈该担心了
Run home. Your mother's probably wondering where you are.
不会  我妈妈知道我在这儿  她同意的
Oh, no, my mom knows where I am. She said it's fine.
我很快发现这姑娘一点也不识趣
It didn't take long to realize this girl could not take a hint.
-三个人在这里太挤了  -我不介意
- It's crowded in here with three people. - I don't mind.
太不识相了
Of any kind.
一起来搬这箱子好吗
You wanna push this one together?
布莱斯  你不是要去帮妈妈吗
Bryce, isn't it time for you to go help your mother?
什么
Huh?
啊对  没错
Oh, yeah.
什么都挡不住她
I mean, nothing would stop her.
我正想叫她滚开时候  最囧的事情发生了
I was about to tell her to get lost when the weirdest thing happened.
真是难以置信
I couldn't believe it.
我居然牵着一个陌生女孩的手
There I was holding hands with this strange girl.
我怎么会这么倒霉
How did I get into this mess?
你好啊
Well, hello.
-你已经认识我儿子了  -是啊
- I see you've met my son. - Uh-huh.
结果  我做了七岁男子汉唯一能做的事
Finally, I did the only manly thing available when you're 7 years old.
可是  我的麻烦还远未结束
However, my troubles were far from over.
当我一踏入埃尔森老师的教室...
The minute I walked into Miss Yelson's classroom...
布莱斯  你来了
Bryce? You're here.
显然
...it was clear:
学校也不是一方净土
School would not be a sanctuary.
嘿  布莱斯  你女朋友呢
Hey, Bryce, where's your girlfriend?
我的一世清名毁了
I was branded for life.
嘿  布莱斯  你怎么不向她求婚呢
Hey, Bryce, why don't you ask her to marry you?
布莱斯和朱莉高高坐树上
Bryce and Juli sitting in a tree
卿卿我我不分离
K-l-S-S-l-N-G
我刚到镇上的第一年就是场灾难
My first year in town was a disaster.
瞧瞧他们
Look at them.
接下来三年也没好到哪去
And the next three weren't much better.
不过终于  在六年级时  我采取了行动
But finally, in the sixth grade, I took action.
我想出了个主意
I hatched the plan.
雪莉
Sherry.
雪莉  等等我
Sherry, wait up.
你好  布莱斯
Hi, Bryce.
我约了雪莉·斯图出去
I asked out Sherry Stalls.
不知你是否愿意去...
I was wondering if you wanted to go...
这个主意的绝妙之处在于
To full appreciate the brilliance of this plan...
朱莉讨厌雪莉·斯图
...you have to understand that Juli hated Sherry Stalls...
尽管我不明就里
...though I never understood why.
雪莉温柔友善  还有着一头浓密的金发
Sherry was nice, friendly and she had a lot of hair.
起先  我妈妈不同意我打耳洞  可我不停请求
At first, my mother wouldn't let me get my ears pierced, but I begged...
我的计划是先和雪莉一起吃饭
The idea was that Sherry would eat with me...
之后我们也许能并肩而行
...maybe we'd walk around together,
这样朱莉大概就会知难而退了
and hopefully Juli would lose interest.
不过我还是不能在十六岁以前打耳洞
But I still can't get the hoops till I'm 16.
真遗憾
Oh, that's a shame.
美兰妮也想打耳洞
So Melanie wanted to get her ears pierced,
她妈妈当然不同意啦
but of course her mother said no.
然后她就大发脾气
So she threw a fit and
把她的强尼·麦瑟斯精选集唱片砸了个稀烂
smashed her Johnny Mathis Greatest Hits album...
于是就被关起来了
...and she got grounded, so
她也不能参加我的睡衣派对了
now she can't come to my pajama sleepover party.
事情进展得异常顺利
Things were unfolding quite nicely.
你的科学展作品准备得怎样了
What are you doing for your science project?
直到被我当作死党的伽利特·艾宾德
That is, until my supposed best friend, Garrett Einbinder...
也对雪莉发起了攻势
...took an interest in Sherry himself.
我打算展示
I was thinking of showing how
不同护发素对头发分叉的影响
split ends react with different hair conditioners.
太有趣了
That's fascinating.
这个重色轻友的叛徒伽利特
Loyalty gave way to desire and Garrett, the turncoat...
告诉了雪莉我的意图
...told Sherry what I was up to.
混蛋
Jerk.
她很生气
She didn't take it well.
再说到朱莉
Word got back to Juli,
她很快又开始含情脉脉地注视我
and pretty soon she started up with the goo-goo eyes again.
不过这次更糟
Only this time it was worse.
她开始闻我
She started sniffing me.
没错  闻我
That's right, sniffing me.
那是干什么呢
What was that all about?
我唯一的慰藉就是期望明年会有所改变
My only consolation was that next year would be different.
上初中学校更大
Junior high, bigger school.
也许我们不会分到一个班  就终于能分开了
Maybe we'd be in different classes and it would finally, finally be over.
我遇到布莱斯·洛斯奇的第一天就怦然心动了
The first day I met Bryce Loski, I flipped.
他的眼睛  那双明亮迷人的眼睛吸引了我
It was those eyes, something in those dazzling eyes.
一起来搬这箱子好吗
You wanna push this one together?
当时  他家刚搬到我家对面
His family had just moved into the neighborhood...
我跑过去帮助他们
...and I'd gone over to help them.
我爬上货车才两分钟
I'd been in the van all of two minutes
他爸爸就叫他去给他妈妈帮忙
when his dad sent him off to help his mom.
看得出来他并不愿意
I could see he didn't wanna go.
于是我跟着他
So I chased after him to see if
看能不能在他进去忙活之前跟他玩一会
we could play a little before he got trapped inside.
后来不知怎的他就握着我的手了
The next thing I know, he's holding my hand...
注视着我的眼睛
...and looking right into my eyes.
我的心跳都停止了
My heart stopped.
就是这种感觉吗
Was this it?
这会是我的初吻吗
Would this be my first kiss?
-可这时他妈妈出来了  -你好啊
- But then his mother came out. - Well, hello.
他很不好意思  羞得满脸通红
And he was so embarrassed, his cheeks turned completely red.
那晚  我躺在床上
I went to bed that night
幻想着那个极可能发生的吻
thinking of the kiss that might have been.
很明显他对我也有意思
I mean, it was clear he had feelings for me,
只是他太害羞而不敢表达
but he was just too shy to show them.
妈妈说男孩子就是这样
My mother said boys were like that.
于是我决定帮助他
So I decided to help him out.
布莱斯  你来啦
Bryce? You're here.
我要给他许多机会来克服害羞
I would give him plenty of opportunity to get over his shyness.
到了六年级  我收敛了不少
By the sixth grade, I'd learned to control myself.
结果雪莉·斯图闯了进来
Then Sherry Stalls entered the picture.
雪莉·斯图不过是个爱发牢骚
Sherry Stalls was nothing but a whiny,
八卦  喜欢暗箭伤人的轻佻女孩
gossipy, backstabbing flirt.
秀发迷人但徒有其表
All hair and no substance.
她过来了
And there she was...
与布莱斯十指紧扣  是我的布莱斯
...holding hands with Bryce. My Bryce.
这个人还等待着我的初吻呢
The one was walking around with my first kiss.
我的对策就是无视她  我知道聪明如布莱斯
My solution was to ignore her. I knew a boy of Bryce's caliber...
终有一天会识穿雪莉·斯图的浅薄
...would eventually see through a shallow conniver like Sherry Stalls.
果然不出一周  他们在午休时分手了
It took all of a week. They broke up at recess.
她很生气
She didn't take it well.
布莱斯逃离了雪莉的魔爪
Now that Bryce was out of Sherry's evil clutches,
他对我的态度也好多了
he started being nicer to me.
-你好  朱莉  -你好  布莱斯
- Hi, Juli. - Hi, Bryce.
他是如此腼腆  如此可爱
He was so shy and so cute...
他的发间散发着淡淡的西瓜味
...and his hair, it smelled like watermelon.
我总是闻不够
I couldn't get enough of it.
一整年我都在偷偷闻着那股西瓜味
I spent the whole year secretly sniffing watermelon...
幻想着我何时能得到我的初吻
...and wondering if I was ever going to get my kiss.
初一时发生了许多变化
Seventh grade brought changes, all right.
不过最大的变化不是发生在学校
But the biggest one didn't happen at school.
而是在家
It happened at home.
我外公搬来与我们同住
My grandfather came to live with us.
妈妈说他总这样呆望是因为他想外婆了
Mom said he stared like that because he missed Grandma.
外公可不会对我说这些
That was not something Grandpa would ever talk about with me.
事实上  他很少跟我说话
As a matter of fact, he never talked about much of anything with me.
直到有天朱莉上了当地的报纸
That is, until Juli appeared in the local newspaper.
-布莱斯  能跟你聊两句吗  -怎么了
- Oh, Bryce. May I speak with you? - What?
坐下吧  孩子
Have a seat, son.
跟我说说你的朋友朱莉·贝克
Tell me about your friend Juli Baker.
朱莉  她不算是我的朋友
Juli. She's not exactly my friend.
是吗  为什么
Oh. Why's that?
你为什么想知道
Why do you wanna know?
上初二的朱莉·贝克登上《梅菲德时报》
Now, Juli Baker did not wind up in The Mayfield Times...
可不是因为什么天才成就
...for being an eighth-grade Einstein.
《梅菲德时报》  13岁女孩抗议伐树
相反  她上了报纸头版
No, she got front-page coverage
是因为她不肯爬下一棵梧桐树
because she refused to climb out of a sycamore tree.
朱莉·贝克和那棵傻乎乎的梧桐树
Juli Baker and that stupid sycamore tree.
她总是以为
She always thought
那树是上帝赐给我们这个小地方的礼物
it was God's gift to our little corner of the universe.
布莱斯  来跟我和我哥哥一起爬树吧
Hey, Bryce. Wanna come climb the tree with me and my brothers?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
布莱斯  快上来  好玩极了
Bryce. Come up here. It's fun.
-你能看到一切  -我来不了
- You can see everything. - I can't.
爸爸要我帮他修...
My dad needs me to help him fix...
修个东西
...a thing.
我得扯个借口
That's all I needed.
和朱莉·贝克一起爬树
Climb up a tree with Juli Baker.
那还不得把我打回小学二年级去
I'd be dragged right back into the second grade.
布莱斯和朱莉高高坐树上
Bryce and Juli sitting in a tree.
你还不如让我一辈子吃素算了
Why don't you just make me eat lima beans for the rest of my life.
还有三个街区
It's three blocks away.
两个街区
Two blocks.
还有一个街区就到了
One block away.
搞得像什么重大消息似的
Like that's valuable information.
我讨厌她一直这样预报
I hate it when she does that.
本来还能对校车不来了抱一丁点指望
I like to think there's at least a chance the bus won't show.
我觉得晨曦中的梧桐树格外美丽  你觉得呢
I think the tree looks particularly beautiful in this light. Don't you?
如果你所说的美丽是指无与伦比的丑陋
If by "beautiful" you mean "unbelievably ugly,"
那么没错  我同意
Then, yes, I would agree.
你眼睛出问题了  真为你惋惜
You're just visually challenged. I feel sorry for you.
"眼睛出问题了"
"Visually challenged"?
这话居然出自一个
This from the girl who lived
自家房子被街坊当成笑柄的女孩之口
in a house that was the joke of the neighborhood?
她家的灌木丛窜得有窗户那么高
They had bushes growing over windows
院子里到处杂草丛生
and weeds all over the place.
搞得我爸爸很无奈
It bugged my dad bigtime.
瞧  他又开始画了
Oh, there he is.
那个自以为是个画家的砖瓦匠
The bricklayer who thinks he's a painter.
还嫌那卡车不够丑吗
That truck's not ugly enough in real life?
他居然还要把它画下来
He's gotta make a painting of it?
不  他画的是风景画  拿到县集市上去卖
No, he does landscapes. Sells them at the county fair.
大家都说他的画很漂亮
People say they're beautiful.
风景画  告诉你吧
Landscapes? Let me tell you something.
如果他肯把他那杂乱的院子稍微收拾一下
The world would have more beauty in it...
这个世界将会变得更美丽
...if he'd do a little landscaping on that piece of crap he calls a yard.
我真同情他妻子  她嫁了个空想家
I feel bad for his wife. She married a dreamer.
因此他们俩总有一人要忍受不幸
Because of that, one of the two of them will always be unhappy.
管他呢  可为什么我们也要受气呢
Yeah, fine. But why do we have to be unhappy?
就如对门的院子让我爸心烦一样
As annoying as the yard was to my dad...
没有比树上的朱莉·贝克更烦人的了
...it was nothing compared to how annoying Juli Baker was in that tree.
还有三个街区
Three blocks away.
每天早上我们都不得不听着
Every morning we had to listen to the sound...
她那不厌其烦的校车预报
...of her blow-by-blow traffic report.
两个街区
Two blocks.
来了
There you go.
为什么要叫《活宝三人组》呢
Why do they call it The Three Stooges?
-我是说明明有五个  -什么
- I mean, there's five of them. - What?
有莫尔  拉瑞  克里  山普  还有卷毛乔
Well, yeah, there's Moe, Larry, Curly, Shemp and Curly Joe.
对  不过每次出场都只有三个
Yeah, but they only have three at a time.
也是
Yeah.
我不喜欢卷毛乔
You know, I hate Curly Joe.
他根本就算不上是活宝
I mean, he shouldn't even be a Stooge.
听着  小姑娘  我就要报警了
Listen, girl, I'm this close to calling the police.
你这是擅闯私人领地  妨碍正常施工
You are trespassing and obstructing progress on a contracted job.
-怎么回事  -要么你自己下来
- What's going on? - Either you come down...
要么我们就把你砍下来了
...or we're gonna cut you down.
布莱斯  你们也爬上来
Bryce, you guys, come up here with me.
如果我们都在树上  他们就不敢砍
They won't cut it down if we're all up here.
-车来了  车来了  -朱莉抓狂了
- Bus, bus, bus. - Juli was frantic.
他们想砍掉她的树
They wanted to cut down her tree.
我真不明白
I couldn't understand why
她怎么那么在乎那棵长得歪七扭八的树
that mutant tangle of gnarly branches meant so much to her.
布莱斯  求你了
Bryce, please.
-我挺同情她  -别管她了
- I felt bad for her. - Leave her.
但我不想因此逃课
But I wasn't about to cut school over it.
快来  哥们儿
Come on, bro.
为什么她不是你的朋友  布莱斯
Why isn't she your friend, Bryce?
你得先了解朱莉
You'd have to know Juli.
我正想了解
Well, I'd like to.
为什么
Why?
那姑娘很有骨气
That girl has an iron backbone.
干嘛不请她过来玩呢
Why don't you invite her over sometime?
很有骨气
An iron backbone?
她就是很倔吧
She's just stubborn...
固执得要命
...and she's pushy beyond belief.
是吗
Is that so?
从二年级起她就一直缠着我
And she's been stalking me since the second grade.
并非人人都能和这样的女孩做邻居
Well, a girl like that doesn't live next door to everyone.
那他们很幸运
Lucky them.
看看这个
Read this.
放下成见
Without prejudice.
好像我还不够了解朱莉·贝克似的
Like I needed to know anything more about Juli Baker.
第二天早上朱莉没去等校车
Juli wasn't at the bus stop the next morning.
第三天早上也没有
Or the morning after that.
她来上学了  可不知道她是怎么来的
She was at school, but you'd never know it.
-小乔   他化了很重的妆  -他又不老
- Little Joe? He's got so much makeup on... - He doesn't age.
我对自己说应该感到高兴才对
I told myself I should be glad about it.
这不正是我想要的吗
I mean, isn't that what I'd always wanted?
但我还是很为她难过
But still, I felt bad for her.
我想去跟她道歉  可转念一想  不行
I was gonna tell her I was sorry, but then I thought, hey, no...
我决不能让朱莉·贝克以为
...that's the last thing I needed:
我想她了
Juli Baker thinking I missed her.
我知道你为何喜欢来这里了
I see why you like to come out here.
你能让你妈也明白就好了
Would you mind explaining it to your mother?
我喜欢看爸爸画画
I loved to watch my father paint.
或者说我是喜欢他边画画边与我聊天
Or really, I loved to hear him talk while he painted.
我就这样了解了爸爸很多的事
I learned a lot about my dad that way.
他与我谈天说地
He told me all sorts of things...
比如他是如何找到送干草的第一份工作的
...like how he got his first job delivering hay
还有他真希望当年能念完大学
and how he'd wished he'd finished college.
有一天  他的话让我很意外
Then one day he surprised me.
你和布莱斯·洛斯奇怎么回事
What's going on with you and, uh, Bryce Loski?
你指什么  没什么啊
What do you mean? Nothing.
好吧
Oh, okay.
是我想多了
My mistake.
你为什么会这么想
Why would you even think that?
不为什么
No reason.
只是你...
Just that you...
老是在说他
...talk about him all the time.
我有吗
I do?
是啊
Mm-hm.
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜是因为他的眼睛吧
I guess it's something about his eyes.
或是因为他的微笑
Or maybe his smile.
那他的人呢
But what about him?
-什么  -你得观其全貌
- What? - You have to look at the whole landscape.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
一幅画并不是各个部分的简单相加
A painting is more than the sum of its parts.
奶牛单独看就是奶牛
A cow by itself is just a cow.
草场就其本身也只是草和花
A meadow by itself is just grass, flowers.
而穿过树枝的阳光也不过是一线光束
And the sun peeking through the trees is just a beam of light.
但当你把它们结合到一起...
But you put them all together...
奇迹就发生了
...and it can be magic.
我并不十分理解他所说的话
I didn't really understand what he was saying
直到那天下午
until one afternoon...
当我爬上那棵梧桐树
...when I was up in the sycamore tree.
我去够一只挂住的风筝
I was rescuing a kite.
风筝挂得很高  是我从未爬上去过的高度
It was a long way up, higher than I'd ever been.
我爬得越高  就越被眼前的美景所震撼
And the higher I got, the more amazed I was by the view.
我开始嗅到微风中的曼妙气息
I began to notice how wonderful the breeze smelled.
像是阳光和野草的芬芳
Like sunshine and wild grass.
我贪婪地呼吸着
I couldn't stop breathing it in...
让最清甜的空气充满身体
filling my lungs with the sweetest smell I'd ever known.
你找到我的风筝了
Hey, you found my kite.
布莱斯  你应该到这上面来看看
Bryce, you should come up here.
太美了
It's so beautiful.
不行  我扭伤了我的...
I can't. I sprained my, um...
我起了疹子
I have a rash.
从那一刻起  这里就成了我的小天地
From that moment on, that became my spot.
我能在那一待几个小时
I could sit there for hours,
就从上面眺望着这个世界
just looking out at the world.
有时候落日是紫色和粉色的
Some days the sunsets would be purple and pink.
有时候则是炽烈的桔黄色
And some days they were a blazing orange...
燃烧着地平线上的云
setting fire to the clouds on the horizon.
有一次看着这样的落日
It was during one of those sunsets that
我突然领悟了爸爸所说的那个概念
my father's idea of the whole being greater than the sum of its parts...
整体大于部分之和
moved from my head to my heart.
有时候我会起得格外早来这里看日出
Some days I would get there extra early to watch the sunrise.
一天早上  我正在用心记下
One morning I was making mental notes...
万道霞光穿透云层的模样
of how the streaks of light were cutting through the clouds...
好回去与爸爸分享
so I could tell my dad...
突然听到下面传来噪音
when I heard a noise below.
不好意思
Excuse me.
不好意思  对不起
Excuse me. I'm sorry,
你不能把车停在那  那是校车站
but you can't park there. That's a bus stop.
你在上面干什么呢
Hey, what are you doing up there?
你不能待在上面  我们要把它砍倒
You can't be up there, we're gonna take this thing down.
-这棵树吗  -是的  下来吧
- The tree? - Yeah. Now come on down.
-谁批准你砍树了  -树的主人
- But who told you, you could cut it down? - The owner.
为什么
Why?
他要盖一座房子  这棵树碍事了
He's gonna build a house, and this tree's in the way.
下来  小姑娘  我们得干活了
So come on, girl, we got work to do.
你不能把它砍倒  就是不能
You can't cut it down. You just can't.
听着  小姑娘  我就要报警了
Listen, girl. I'm this close to calling the police.
你这是擅闯私人领地  妨碍正常施工
You are trespassing and obstructing progress on a contracted job.
要么你自己下来  要么我们就把你砍下来了
Now either you come down, or we're gonna cut you down.
来啊  你们砍吧
Go ahead. Cut me down.
我不下去  我绝不下去
I'm not coming down. I'm never coming down.
布莱斯  你们也爬上来
Bryce. You guys, come up here with me.
如果我们都在树上  他们就不敢砍了
They won't cut it down if we're all up here.
布莱斯  求你了  别让他们砍树
Bryce, please don't let them do this.
你们上来啊
Come on, you guys.
布莱斯  求你了
Bryce, please.
你们不用爬这么高  上来一点就行了
You don't have to come up this high. Just a little ways.
布莱斯  求你了  求你了
Bryce, please. Please.
后来的事情我记不清了
What happened after that was a blur.
好像整个镇上的人都来了
It seemed like the whole town was there.
但我还是没动
But still I wouldn't move.
后来我爸爸来了
Then my father showed up.
他说服了一个消防员  让他爬上来找我
He talked a fireman into letting him come up to where I was.
亲爱的  现在该下来了
Sweetie, it's time to come down.
爸爸  求你别让他们砍树
Daddy, please don't let them do this.
-亲爱的  -爸爸  你看
- Sweetie... - Daddy, look.
你能看到一切  从这里你能看到全世界
You can see everything. You can see the whole world from here.
什么美景都没我女儿的安全重要
No view is worth my daughter's safety.
来吧
Now, come on.
不要
I can't.
朱莉安娜  现在该下来了
Julianna, it's time to come down now.
求你了  爸爸
Please, Daddy.
该下来了
It's time.
事情就是这样
And that was it.
我哭了足有两个星期
I must've cried for two weeks straight.
当然  我还是去上学了  尽力表现好点
Oh, sure, I went to school and did the best I could...
但一切似乎都不重要了
but nothing seemed to matter.
-朱莉  -啊
- Juli? - Huh?
你知道答案是什么吗
Do you know the answer?
伯罗奔尼撒战争
Uh, the Peloponnesian War?
你真是答非所问
I'm sure that's the answer to something...
我问的是菱形的面积
but I was looking for the area of a rhomboid.
不知怎么了  菱形和等腰直角三角形
Somehow, rhomboids and isosceles right triangles...
似乎没那么重要了
didn't seem so important.
我骑车去上学  这样就不用看见那个树桩
I rode my bike so I wouldn't have to pass by the stump...
那曾经是地球上最壮美的梧桐树
that used to be the earth's most magnificent sycamore tree.
但不论做什么  我都在想着它
But no matter what I did, I couldn't stop thinking about it.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
只是棵树而已
It was just a tree.
不  不只是棵树
No, it wasn't just a tree.
我希望你永远不要忘记在上面的感觉
I never want you to forget how you felt when you were up there.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
这幅画每天随我起床
It was the first thing I saw every morning...
伴我入眠
and the last thing I saw before I went to sleep.
当我看到它不再哭泣时
And once I could look at it without crying...
我看到了树以外的东西
I saw more than the tree
明白了在它上面对我的意义
and what being up there meant to me.
那天起  我看周围事物的眼光开始改变
I saw the day that my view of things around me started changing.
然后我在想
And I wondered,
我对布莱斯的感觉还和以前一样吗
did I still feel the same things about Bryce?
我一直对蛋没什么特别感觉
I've never been a huge fan of eggs.
我的意思是  有也可以  没有也行
I mean, I could always just take them or leave them.
直到那天在斯凯勒·布朗的车库里
That is, until one day in Skyler Brown's garage...
我对蛋的感觉彻底固定了
when my feelings about eggs were solidified.
诸位诸位  艾娜发现它的早餐了
Hey, hey, hey. Guys. Edna's found her breakfast.
我是说  如果粘乎乎的爬虫喜欢吃这东西
I mean, if a slimy reptile found them appetizing...
那我是绝对不会再碰了
there was certainly no place for them in my diet.
实在是太酷了
Oh, man, that's so cool.
它甚至不用嚼
She doesn't even have to chew.
想想  省了多少时间啊
I mean, think of all the time you'd save.
我本来一辈子都不会知道蛇是生吞鸡蛋的
I could've gone my whole life not knowing that snakes eat eggs raw...
都是因为琳妮塔
if it hadn't been for Lynetta.
她和斯凯勒·布朗关系不一般
She had a major-league thing for Skyler Brown.
我觉得很恶心
I think it's gross.
他和朱莉的哥哥马特和马克组了个乐队
He and Juli's brothers, Matt and Mark, had formed a band.
琳妮塔经常去看他们排练
And Lynetta would watch them practice.
真是太棒了
That is so neat.
怎么样  布莱斯
How about that, huh, Bryce?
是啊  很棒
Yeah. Neat.
布莱斯  你觉得它要怎么消化这蛋
So, Brycie, how do you think he's gonna digest that?
-用胃酸吗  -估计你就会这样想
- Stomach acid? - You'd like to think that.
大家安静  看好了
Wait, everybody quiet. Here he goes.
煎荷包蛋了
Eggs over easy.
恶心  恶心
Gross. Gross, gross, gross.
等等  你还没看见最精彩的呢
Wait, wait. You haven't seen the best part.
真恶心
Gross.
我试图保持淡定  但不太成功
I tried to be casual about it, but it didn't take.
我开始做噩梦
I started having bad dreams.
梦到我被困在一个巨大的蛋里
I'd be trapped inside a huge egg...
一只怪兽正要张开大嘴把我吞掉
and this monster would open his jaws and start to devour me.
幸好这时我醒了
I'd wake up just in time.
然后真正的噩梦开始了
Then the real nightmare began.
布莱斯  我给你们拿了些这个
Hi, Bryce. I brought these over for you and your family.
-我的鸡下蛋了  -什么
- My chickens are laying eggs. - What?
你记得小黑  小黄
You remember Abby and Bonnie
阿扁  阿呆  点点和花花吗
and Clyde and Dexter and Eunice and Florence?
-我在科技展上孵化的  -怎么可能忘
- The ones I hatched for the science fair. - How could I forget?
这就是经典的朱莉·贝克
It was classic Juli Baker.
她在展览上出尽风头
She totally dominated the fair.
你想  她做的项目就是观察无聊的孵蛋过程
And get this, her project was all about watching boring eggs hatch.
而我可是有一座实景喷发的火山啊
I mean, here I had a live-action erupting volcano...
但所有人都在关注朱莉的无聊小鸡
and all anyone cared about was Juli's boring chicks...
从它们的无聊蛋壳里破壳而出
breaking out of their boring shells.
最后一只好像要出来了
Oh, I think the last one's hatching.
-出来了  -出来了
- It's hatching. - Oh, it's hatching.
孩子们  过来
Kids, come over here.
她赢了  我输了
But hey, she won. I lost.
我总得不到大家垂青
I've never been one to dwell.
出来了
Here it comes.
但这并不意味着我得吃她恶心的鸡蛋
But that didn't mean I had to eat her lousy eggs.
朱莉真好  送鸡蛋给我们吃
I think it was very sweet of Juli to bring us those eggs.
才不稀罕  我明早还吃麦片
I don't care. I'm still having cereal tomorrow.
我们怎么知道那些蛋里有没有小鸡
Yeah, how do we know there's no chicks in one of those eggs?
我小时候常吃农场的新鲜土鸡蛋  非常好吃
I used to eat farm-fresh eggs when I was a kid. They were delicious.
好吧  是非常好
Yeah, well, that's all well and good...
但万一敲开  结果出来一只死小鸡怎么办
but what if we crack one open and a dead chick falls out?
他们有公鸡吗
Do they have a rooster?
如果没有公鸡  那蛋就不会受精
If they don't have a rooster the eggs can't be fertile.
如果他们养了公鸡  我们会知道的
And if they had a rooster, we'd know.
所有邻居都会知道的
The whole neighborhood would know.
也许他们把它喔喔弄残了
Maybe they got it de-yodeled.
"喔喔弄残了"
"De-yodeled"?
就是把它的喔喔喔给弄废了
You know. De-cock-a-doodle-doo'd.
什么乱七八糟的
What the hell are you talking about?
就像把狗弄哑那样
Like they de-bark dogs.
布莱斯  你干嘛不直接问朱莉呢
Bryce, why don't you just ask Juli?
-我不觉得...  -什么
- I don't think that... - What?
-你怕和她说话吗  -我才不怕和她说话
- You afraid to talk to her? - I'm not afraid to talk to her.
我知道那是你  那我是什么
I know you are, but what am I?
好了  问问她就知道了
Okay. Just talk to her and find out.
你怎么知道什么样的是公鸡
How do you tell if one's a rooster?
公鸡更大  羽毛更长
Well, a rooster's bigger. Longer feathers.
它们头上长着红色的东西
They've got that red stuff growing out of their head.
脖子周围也有
And around their neck too.
那应该不难认
That shouldn't be too hard to spot.
不过话说回来
Although, come to think of it,
其它鸡也有那种红色肉瘤
chickens have the rubbery red stuff too.
只是没那么大
Just not as much.
伽利特对公鸡的精通
Garrett's expertise in roosters...
是我们避免与朱莉·贝克接触的基石
was the cornerstone of our plan to avoid contact with Juli Baker.
剩下要做的就是去偷窥她家后院了
The balance of which involved spying over her back fence.
-快来  快来  -嘘  嘘
- Come on, come on. - Shh. Shh.
就这里
Over here.
我看不见那些蠢鸡
I can't see the stupid chickens.
我们得让它们从鸡窝里出来
We gotta get them out of the coop.
那是公鸡吗
Is that a rooster?
不  看起来像普通鸡
No, it looks like a chicken.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
一看就知道
It just does.
看到了吧  这就是精通
See what I mean? Expertise.
-嘘  嘘  -怎么了
- Shh, shh! - What?
朱莉
Juli.
快来吃
Here, guys.
继续  快吃吧
Go on, there you go.
-给  接着吃  -没错  都是普通鸡
- Here, guys. Go on. - Yeah, they're all chickens.
-没有公鸡吗  -我不是刚说了吗
- There's no rooster? - What did I just say?
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
-没有那种昂首阔步的鸡  -给  来啊
- Well, none of them are strutting. - Here, come on.
-公鸡昂首阔步吗  -来吃啊
- Roosters strut? - Come on, guys.
-我不是刚说了吗  -给
- What did I just say? - Here.
而且它们几乎都没长红色肉瘤
Plus, hardly any of them have any rubbery red stuff.
-你在干什么  -它们绝对都是普通鸡
- What are you doing? - Yeah. They're definitely all chickens.
都是普通鸡
They're all chickens.
我为你骄傲  布莱斯
I'm proud of you, Bryce.
-你克服了自己的恐惧  -什么
- You overcame your fear. - Huh?
-你和她说话了  -噢  是啊
- You talked to her. - Oh, heh. Yeah.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
她怎么和你说的  都是普通鸡吗
That's what she told you? They're all chickens?
是啊
Yeah.
她是个天才  你们都是天才
She's a genius. You're both genius...
当然都是普通鸡
Of course they're all chickens.
公鸡也是普通鸡  问题是
A rooster's a chicken. The question is:
有没有公鸡  或者说是否全是母鸡
Is one of them a rooster or are they all hens?
母鸡   什么时候提到过母鸡
Hens? Who said anything about hens?
我明白了
Then it hit me.
伽利特根本不懂鸡
Garrett didn't know jack shit about chickens.
-公鸡都昂首阔步是吗  -是的  没错
- Do roosters strut? - Yes, they do.
这又有什么关系
What does that have to do with anything?
它们都是母鸡
They're all hens.
重要的是鸡蛋没问题就行
Well, the main thing is the eggs are okay.
没事了
It's all settled.
对我来说可不是
Not for me.
我绝对不吃
There was no way I was ever gonna eat anything...
和朱莉·贝克有关的任何东西
that had anything to do with Juli Baker.
我不吃那些蛋
I'm not eating them.
为什么呢
Well, why not?
你看见他们的院子了吗  真是...
Have you seen their yard? It's...
连根草都没有  全是泥巴和鸡屎
There's not even any grass. It's all mud and chicken turds.
恶心  沙门氏菌
Ew. Gross. Salmonella.
你觉得这些蛋会有沙门氏菌吗
Do you suppose they could have salmonella?
-可能性不大  -何必要冒险呢
- It's not very likely. - Why take the risk?
那这些鸡蛋怎么办
What do we do with the eggs?
退回去
Give them back.
-退回去   给朱莉   -当然
- Give them back? To Juli? - Sure.
你和她说过话了  对吧  不会要你命的
You talked to her before, right? It didn't kill you.
那我怎么说啊
Well, what do I say?
跟她说我们不吃鸡蛋
Tell her we don't eat eggs.
我们全家都对鸡蛋过敏之类的
Uh, we're allergic to them or something.
动动脑子
Come on, use your brains.
撒谎似乎不大好
It didn't feel right to lie.
而且  连初一的学生都知道
Besides, even a seventh grader would know
不可能全家都对鸡蛋过敏的
that entire families aren't allergic to eggs.
但我也不想伤害她的感情
But I didn't wanna hurt her feelings either.
所以我别无选择了
So that left me with only one option.
于是在我与朱莉·贝克的拉锯战中
And thus another near-death experience...
又一次致命接触被成功避免了
in my ongoing saga with juli Baker had been successfully avoided.
直到一周后
Until one week later.
布莱斯  又给你拿了些鸡蛋
Hi, Bryce. Brought you some more eggs.
-谢谢  -你家人喜欢上一批吗
- Thanks. - Did your family like the first batch?
还用问吗
Do you even have to ask?
太好了  学校见
Great. See you at school.
我本以为这是一次性事件
What I hoped would be a one-time event...
可这只是一段谎言阴谋和欺骗生涯的开始
was just the beginning of a life consumed with lies, intrigue and deception.
每天早上我都盯着朱莉
Every morning I'd be on the lookout for Juli...
这样如果她要来
so if she happened to come,
我就能在她敲门之前把门打开
I could whip the door open before she knocked.
谢谢
Thanks.
然后在有人注意到之前把鸡蛋扔掉
Then I'd dump the eggs before anyone noticed.
这是为什么  为什么我就是没法面对她
And why? Why couldn't I just face her?
为什么我就不能说
Why couldn't I just say:
不  谢谢  不想要
"No, thanks. Don't want them.
不需要  拿去给蛇吃吧
Don't need them. Give them to the snake"?
我是真的怕伤了她的感情呢
Was I really afraid of hurting her feelings...
还是因为我怕她呢
or was I just afraid of her?
现在  你要确定你...
Now, you wanna make sure you get it...
最初布贝老师建议我选孵蛋作科研课题时
When Mrs. Brubeck first suggested hatching eggs as my science project...
我还觉得没多大意思
I was less than excited.
直到我第一次看到生命的迹象
That is, until I saw my first sign of life.
那就是吗
Is that it?
-那个就是胚胎  -哇
- That's the embryo. Heh. - Wow.
-看起来像个豆子  -确实
- It looks like a bean. - It does.
试试别的鸡蛋
Let's try the other ones.
突然感觉就真实起来了
Suddenly it felt real.
所有的蛋都是有生命的
All the eggs were alive.
就好象每个蛋里面都有一个豆子宝宝
There were, like, little bean babies inside every one.
科学展那天  六个蛋全都孵出小鸡了
On the day of the fair, all six chicks hatched.
真没想到啊
What are the odds?
科学展
今年的一等奖由朱莉·贝克获得
This year's top prize goes to Juli Baker...
她获奖的的出色项目是
for her wonderful project:
"一只鸡的诞生"
"A Chicken is Born."
我得了第一名
I won first place.
这很酷  但我真正关心的是我的小鸡们
And that was cool, but all I really cared about were my chicks.
来吧  快吃吧
There you go. There you go, guys.
我妈妈对养鸡没多大兴趣
My mom wasn't crazy about us raising chickens.
可我再三央求
But I begged and pleaded.
我跟她说我会打理一切  我说到做到了
I told her I would take care of everything. And I did.
阿扁在哪
Where's Clyde?
阿扁
Clyde?
阿扁  怎么了
Hey, Clyde. What's the matter?
你还好吧  你不饿吗
Are you okay? Aren't you hungry?
过来  到这来  怎么了宝贝
Come on. Come here. What's wrong, baby?
过来
Come here.
你不应该叫阿扁  叫阿珍才对
Hey, you're not Clyde. You're Clydette.
妈妈
Mom!
结果  我的鸡下的蛋我们都吃不完
As it turned out, my hens laid more eggs than we could eat.
一开始我们还想努力赶上进度
At first we tried to keep up...
但是在一个月的煎炒烹炸之后
but after a month of boiling, frying and deviling...
就像电影《变形怪体》里一样
like that movie The Blob,
我们被鸡蛋打败了
we were being overtaken by eggs.
当邻居斯杜比太太来敲门时  转机来了
Then opportunity in the form of our neighbor, Mrs. Steuby, knocked.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, dear.
如果你有多余的鸡蛋  我很乐意买
If you ever have any extra, I'd be happy to buy them from you.
-真的吗  -当然
- Really? - Certainly.
我还知道赫尔姆斯太太也想要
And I happen to know that Mrs. Helms would be interested as well.
-太好了  -没什么比新鲜鸡蛋更好了
- Great. - Nothing like fresh eggs.
谢谢  斯杜比太太
Thanks, Mrs. Steuby.
可不是么  亲爱的  再见
You bet, dear. Bye.
有了斯杜比太太和赫尔姆斯太太
Between Mrs. Steuby and Mrs. Helms,
我鸡蛋过剩的问题解决了
my egg overflow problem was solved.
我想到也该拿点鸡蛋给洛斯奇太太
Then I realized that Mrs. Loski deserved eggs too.
但我觉得不该对她收费
But I didn't think it would be right to charge her.
她是个非常好的邻居
She had been such a good neighbor,
我们东西用完时她会借给我们
lending us supplies when we ran out...
我们车坏时会让我妈搭车
...giving my mother a ride when our car wouldn't start...
送她点鸡蛋真是微不足道
...it was the least I could do.
再说  就算被布莱斯撞见
Besides, if I happened to run into Bryce,
也不会是世界末日
that wouldn't be the end of the world.
嗨  布莱斯
Hi, Bryce.
到我第三次给洛斯奇家送蛋时
By the third time I brought eggs over to the Loskis...
我意识到布莱斯在等我
...I realized Bryce was waiting for me.
等着打开门说
Waiting to pull open the door and say,
"谢谢  朱莉  学校见"
"Thanks, Juli. See you at school."
回报是  我能和世上最明亮迷人的
And in return, I got a few moments alone...
那双眼睛独处片刻
...with the world's most dazzling eyes.
谢谢  朱莉  学校见
Thanks, Juli. See you at school.
真是太值了
It was a bargain.
直到某一天  就不再是这样了
Until the day it wasn't.
那是在梧桐树被砍倒两星期后
It was two weeks after the sycamore tree was cut down...
我正开始恢复正常
...and I was just starting to feel normal again.
嗨  朱莉  真准时
Hey, Juli. Right on schedule.
嗯  风雨无阻
Yeah, well, neither rain nor sleet.
-嗯   -就像邮差那样
- Huh? - You know, the mailman thing?
哦对
Oh. Right.
那  你还会坐校车吗
So, um, will you start riding the bus again?
不知道  自那之后我就没再坐过
I don't know. I haven't been up there since...
那里看起来没那么糟了  都清理干净了
It doesn't look so bad anymore. It's all cleared away.
我得准备上学了
Well, um, I better get ready for school.
学校见吧
Guess I'll see you there.
学校见
See you.
布莱斯说的或许没错
Maybe Bryce was right.
也许我该恢复乘校车了
Maybe it was time I started riding the bus again.
他的意思不就是希望我去坐车嘛
After all, didn't he just tell me he wanted me to?
布莱斯·洛斯奇是想我了吧
Could it be that Bryce Loski actually misses me?
朱莉  你还在这干嘛
Juli? What are you still doing here?
只是在想事情
I was just thinking.
今天是收垃圾的日子  垃圾桶在门口
It's pickup day. The cans are in front.
知道  要帮忙吗
I know. You need some help?
不用  我晚点再扔吧
No. Maybe I'll do it later.
那些是我的蛋吗
Are those my eggs?
嗯  我失手摔地上了
Yeah. Yeah, I dropped them.
它们根本没破
They're not broken.
为什么扔掉
Why are you throwing them away?
你不想要吗
Don't you want them?
不是我  我爸觉得不值得冒风险
It wasn't me. My dad didn't think it was worth the risk.
风险   什么风险
Risk? What risk?
沙门氏菌
Salmonella.
你说什么啊  他怕中毒吗
What are you talking about? He's afraid of being poisoned?
朱莉  看看你们后院  真是一团糟
Well, Juli, I mean, look at your back yard. It's a complete mess.
到处都是鸡屎
It's, like, covered in turds.
乱讲  我每天都给小鸡们清扫的
That's not true. I clean up after my girls every day.
我们只是不想伤害你的感情
We just didn't wanna hurt your feelings.
你每次都把它们扔掉吗
Have you always thrown them away?
斯杜比太太和赫尔姆斯太太可是花钱买我的蛋
You know, Mrs. Steuby and Mrs. Helms pay me for my eggs.
-真的   -一打6毛钱
- They do? - They pay me 60 cents a dozen.
我不知道
I didn't know.
你怎么能这样
How could you?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你才不会
No, you're not.
不久我意识到
It didn't take me long to realize that
我和朱莉·贝克的老问题换成了新问题
I'd traded in my old problems with Juli Baker for a whole set of new ones.
她生我的气比她烦扰我更糟糕
It was actually worse having her mad at me than having her annoy me.
她对我的不理不睬一直在提醒着我
The way she ignored me was a constant reminder...
我是个混蛋
...that I'd been a jerk.
一天  我和伽利特打完篮球回家
Then one day I was coming home from playing basketball with Garrett...
事情变得很蹊跷
...and things got weird.
别这么胆小  加把劲  你不会伤害它们的
Don't be so timid. Come on, you won't hurt them.
-像这样   -对  就是这样
- Like this?  - Yeah, that's it.
我外公
My grandfather.
我从来看他都是穿拖鞋的
All I ever saw him wear was slippers.
今天不知他从哪弄了双工靴穿上了
Now, where did he get those work boots?
我忍不住往那边看
I couldn't stop looking over there.
结果越看越来气
And the more I looked, the madder I got.
我外公一小时和朱莉说的话
My grandfather had already said more to Juli in one hour...
比和我们住在一起对我说过的全部话都多
...than he'd said to me in the whole time he'd been living with us.
我还从没见他开怀大笑过
I was pretty sure I'd never seen him laugh.
他和朱莉·贝克究竟怎么回事呢
And what was his deal with Juli Baker?
嗨  外公
Hi, Grandpa.
朱莉把蛋的事告诉我了
Juli told me about the eggs.
知道吗  布莱斯
You know, Bryce...
一个人的品性在年少时就定型了
...one's character is set at an early age.
我不想看到你误入歧途
I'd hate to see you swim out so far you can't swim back.
什么
Sir?
这是诚信问题  孩子
It's about honesty, son.
开始的一点小小不悦
Sometimes a little discomfort in the beginning...
往往能省却之后的很多痛苦
...can save a whole lot of pain down the road.
要说记仇的本事
When it came to holding a grudge,
朱莉·贝克真是有一套
Juli Baker was truly impressive.
整个星期我在学校都试着接近她
All week I tried to approach her at school.
她总能想办法避开我
She'd always find some way to duck me.
而只要她在她家院子里
And whenever she was in her yard,
外公总和她一起
Grandpa was always there with her.
终于  一个星期六我找到了机会
Finally, one Saturday I saw my opening.
外公到城里买止痛膏去了
My grandfather had gone into town to buy some Bengay.
估计收拾庭院的活儿开始让他吃不消了
I guess the yard work was starting to get to him.
看起来真不错
It's looking real good.
谢谢  大部分都是切特做的
Thanks. Chet did most of it.
我为我的行为道歉
I'm sorry for what I did.
我真不明白  布莱斯  为何不直接告诉我
I just don't get it, Bryce. Why didn't you just tell me?
不知道  我的做法真蠢
I don't know. It was dumb.
我也不该瞎说你家的院子
And I shouldn't have said anything about your yard, either.
这样不对
It wasn't right.
也许这样正好
Maybe it's all for the best.
我是说  我从切特那学到这么多  真是太好了
I mean, look, I learned so much from Chet, it's amazing.
你真幸运
You're lucky.
我都没有爷爷奶奶了
I don't even have grandparents anymore.
我很替他难过
I feel sorry for him.
他很想念你外婆
He misses your grandma.
你能相信吗  他说我让他想起了她
Can you believe it? He says I remind him of her.
-什么  -我知道有点怪  你没有听错
- What? - I know. That's what I said.
但他的用意很好  是说她的精神方面
But he meant it in a nice way. Something about her spirit.
这样啊
Yeah...
祝这些草好运  我相信长出来一定很棒
Good luck with the grass. I'm sure it'll come up great.
谢谢
Thanks.
回头见
I guess I'll see you around.
好
I guess so.
《波纳扎》
虽然朱莉接受我道歉并不像我希望的那样
While Juli's acceptance of my apology was not all that I'd hoped for...
但至少鸡蛋风波终于过去了
...at least the eggs thing was finally behind me.
几个月来我第一次能安心看《波纳扎》了
The first time in months I could truly enjoy Bonanza.
你去哪儿  怎么穿成那样
Where you going and why you dressed like that?
去斯凯勒家
Skyler's.
马特和马克带来了录音设备
Matt and Mark are bringing over recording stuff
他们准备录试唱样带
and they're gonna make a demo.
样带   搞得好像他们知道怎么弄似的
Demo? Like they know how to make a demo.
-你都不认识人家  -不必认识  我知道这号人
- You don't even know them.  - I don't have to. I know the type.
-你一无所知  -别用这语气和我说话
- You don't know anything.  - Don't talk to me like that.
-我要迟到了  -11点前回来
- I'm late.  - Be back by 11.
对  一切都恢复正常了
Yep. Everything was back to normal.
那丫头片子把你累坏了吧
Is that girl working you too hard?
她的名字叫朱莉  她也没把我累着
That girl's name is Juli. And, no, she isn't working me too hard.
你还挺关心她的嘛
You've developed quite a soft spot for her, huh?
斯蒂文
Steven.
帕茜  我只是想知道你爸哪来这么大劲头
No, Patsy. Just wanna find out why your father has the energy...
跑去跟一个陌生人交朋友
...to befriend a complete stranger...
而他都不愿和自己的外孙玩玩棒球
...when he won't throw a baseball around with his own grandson.
-没事  爸  -不  这样不对
- It's okay, Dad.  - No, it's not okay.
朱莉让他想到外婆
Juli reminds him of Grandma.
想到瑞妮
Of Renee? Heh.
真可笑
That's ridiculous.
你知道贝克家为何不修理院子吗
You know why the Bakers haven't fixed their yard?
是因为太忙于画他的烂画了吧
Yeah, because he's too busy with his paint-by-numbers kit.
如果你有个严重残疾的兄弟  你会怎么做
If you had a brother with a severe handicap, what would you do?
怎么会扯上这个
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
朱莉的父亲有个智障的兄弟
Juli's father has a retarded brother.
那又怎样  那院子不会是他兄弟弄的吧
So what? He's not the gardener, is he? Heh.
斯蒂文
Steven.
开个玩笑
It was a joke.
其他人也会有家庭问题
You know, other people have family troubles...
而人家也能修理自家的草坪
...and they manage to mow their own lawns.
真不知他们对拥有家园的自豪感在哪儿
I don't know where their pride in ownership is.
那房子不是他们的
They don't own that house.
应该是房东修理才对
The landlord's supposed to maintain it.
贝克先生把多出的每分钱都用于照顾弟弟
Mr. Baker puts every extra penny he has into caring for his brother.
不是有政府的护理机构管这种事吗
Don't they have government facilities for that sort of thing?
可能他们认为私人护理机构对他更好
Maybe they thought that a private facility would be better for him.
无论怎样  他们家染色体异常
Either way, it's not our fault
这可不是我们的错
that their family has some chromosomal abnormality.
和染色体没关系
It has nothing to do with chromosomes.
朱莉的叔叔出生时
When Juli's uncle was born,
脖子被脐带缠住了
he had the umbilical cord wrapped around his neck.
如果有足够的氧气
If he'd had enough oxygen,
他也会像你的儿子一样是个好宝宝
he would've been a perfect little baby, just like your son.
真扯淡  切特
Goddamn it, Chet.
-帕茜  -让我自己待会儿
- Patsy? Patsy?  - Leave me alone!
抱歉
Sorry about that.
妈妈怎么这么伤心
Why is Mom so upset?
因为...
Because...
还好上帝保佑
...but for the grace of God...
你妈差点和贝克先生的处境一样
...your mother could be standing in Mr. Baker's shoes.
她兄弟脖子也被脐带缠住了
Did her brother have the cord wrapped around his neck too?
是你
You did.
幸好接产医生反应及时  把脐带解开了
Luckily, the doctor who delivered you was on the ball and got it untangled...
不然那种事是极有可能的
...but it easily could've gone the other way.
-想出去走走吗  -嗯
- Wanna go for a walk?  - Huh?
出去走走有助于清理思绪
I find it helps clear the mind.
如果我那样了他们会把我怎样
What would they have done with me?
你不该琢磨那些也许会发生的事  布莱斯
You can't dwell on something that might've been, Bryce.
我爸说话的口气
The way my dad was talking,
听起来就像会把我丢进疯人院
sounds like he would've thrown me in a nuthouse.
不不  这么说不公平
No, no. Now, that's not fair.
你不能用未发生之事来谴责他
You can't condemn him for something he hasn't done.
这里就是那树的位置  是吗
This is where that tree was, wasn't it?
嗯
Yeah.
景色一定很壮观
Must've been a spectacular view.
她是很不错的女孩儿
She's quite a girl.
我们中有的人暗淡无光
Some of us get dipped in flat...
有的色泽艳丽
...some in satin...
有的则光彩照人
...some in gloss.
但是偶尔
But every once in a while...
你也会遇到色彩斑斓的人
...you find someone who's iridescent.
当你真遇到时
And when you do...
其他一切都不重要了
...nothing will ever compare.
暗淡无光  光彩照人  色彩斑斓
Flat, glossy, iridescent?
那究竟是什么意思
What the hell did that mean?
朱莉·贝克在我看来一直很普通而已
Juli Baker had always just seemed plain to me.
直到现在
Until now.
还有她描述在那棵树上的感觉的方式
And the way she talked about what it felt like to be up in that tree...
被高高托举于大地之上  清风吹拂
...to be held above the earth, brushed by the wind.
哪个初中生会那样说
Who in junior high talks like that?
这种奇怪的感觉开始令我很不安
This weird feeling started taking over in the pit of my stomach...
我不喜欢这感觉
...and I didn't like it.
我正在越陷越深
I was slipping, man.
得想办法停下来了
And it was time to get a grip.
之前我从未因我们住的地方感到羞愧
I'd never been embarrassed by where we lived before.
我也从未想过钱
I also never really thought about money.
我知道我们并不富裕
I knew we weren't rich,
但我没觉得我们缺少什么
but I didn't feel like we were missing anything.
直到布莱斯·洛斯奇把我们家称为一团糟
That is, until Bryce Loski called our home a complete mess.
-请教芳名  -请教芳名
- What's your name?  - What's your name?
玛丽还是苏
Is it Mary or Sue?
请教芳名
What's your name?
我有机会吗
Do I stand a chance with you?
魅力如你之人
It's so hard to find a personality
真是众里难寻
With charms like yours for me
我得做点什么  我知道该做什么
I had to do something and I knew what it was.
请教芳名
What's your name?
-听起来真不错  -嗯
- Oh, you're sounding really good. - Yeah.
我们要在斯凯勒的车库里录这首歌
We'll record it in Skyler's garage.
这是个很棒的计划
That's a wonderful project.
说到计划  我想修理下院子会很不错
Speaking of projects, I was thinking it might be cool to fix up the yard.
-什么  -我是说  草种能花多少钱呢
- What?  - I mean, how much can grass seed cost?
我可以种块草坪  也许再种些花
I could plant a lawn, maybe some flowers.
甚至弄个栅栏
I could even put up a fence.
宝贝  那可是笔大开销
Honey, that's a major undertaking.
-我可以用我卖鸡蛋的钱支付  -不  那是你的钱
- I could pay for it with my egg money.  - No. That's your money.
这些事应该房东做才对
The landlord should be the one taking care of all this.
但他没做  我们又住在这儿
But he doesn't. And we live here.
看上去太糟糕了
And it looks so bad.
朱莉
Jules.
怎么了
What's going on?
没什么  爸爸
Nothing, Dad.
没关系的  甜心
It's okay, sweetheart.
告诉我们吧
You can tell us.
洛斯奇家把我的鸡蛋全扔了
The Loskis have been throwing away my eggs
因为他们担心有沙门氏菌
because they're afraid of salmonella.
因为我们的院子一团糟
Because our yard is such a mess.
帕茜这么说的吗
Did Patsy say that?
不是  布莱斯说的
No. Bryce did.
但肯定一家人讨论过
But it must have been a family discussion.
一个小男孩是不会那样想的
A boy doesn't come up with that on his own.
-谁在乎他们怎么想  -对  谁在乎呢
- Who cares what they think?  - Yeah, who cares?
-我在乎  -翠娜
- I care.  - Trina.
我们别为这个动气好吗
Let's not get into this.
不  我受够了  理查德
No, I'm tired of living like this, Richard.
我受够了总要做零工来贴补家用
I'm tired of having to take temp jobs just to make ends meet.
我受够了老得用椅子顶住那洗衣机
I'm tired of having to push a chair up against the washing machine...
才能关上门
...just to keep the door shut.
我受够了每当我们的吸尘器坏掉时
I'm tired of having to borrow Mrs. Steuby's vacuum cleaner...
都要去借斯杜比太太的
...every time ours breaks down.
你觉得我想让大家过这样的日子吗
Do you think this is the life I pictured for us?
有时为了该做的事  你就得做点牺牲
Sometimes you have to sacrifice to do the right thing.
我们每次商量后都一致认为
We always end up agreeing
送丹尼去德文霍斯特是应该的
that Devonhurst is the right thing for Daniel.
也许我们该想想  为自己什么是该做的了
Well, maybe we should start thinking about what's right for us.
女儿因我们没有修理自己的院子而遭耻笑
Our daughter is suffering because we won't fix up our own yard.
这不是我们的院子
It's not our yard.
你怎能那么说  理查德
How can you say that, Richard? How?
我们在这住了12年
We've lived here for 12 years...
12年来我们一直说只是暂住  但并不是
...and for 12 years we've been saying it's temporary, but it's not.
这就是我们的家
This is our home.
想住一个可以引以为豪的地方有错吗
Is it wrong to wanna live somewhere you can be proud of?
攒够钱送孩子去大学有错吗
To have enough to send your kids to college?
或许是时候考虑一下政府的福利机构了
Maybe it's time we considered government care.
决不能把我兄弟送那儿去
We are not moving my brother.
他比你自己的孩子更重要吗
He's more important than your own children?
-爸  -你竟敢这么说
- Dad!  - How dare you!
别吵了  爸  别吵了
Stop it, Dad! Please, just stop.
对不起  朱莉安娜  这不是你的错
I'm sorry. Julianna, this is not your fault.
我们会想出办法的  我保证
We'll work this out, I promise.
那是我第一次听到我父母大吵
That was the first time I ever heard my parents really yell at each other.
今晚的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about tonight.
那晚他们分别来到我房间
That night they each came into my room.
父亲讲了他弟弟的事  以及他如何爱他
My father talked about his brother and how much he loved him...
以及他如何答应父母要一直照顾他
...and how he promised his parents he'd always take care of him.
母亲则告诉我  她有多爱我的父亲
My mother talked about how much she loved my father...
爱他的坚强和善良
...for his strength and kind heart.
当吻我晚安时
When she kissed me good night...
她在我耳边说  在所有上天给她的赐福中
...she whispered that of all her many blessings,
我是最重要的
I was her best.
我为爸爸感到难过
I felt sorry for my father.
也为妈妈难过
I felt sorry for my mother.
不过  拥有他们我觉得很幸运
But most of all, I felt lucky for me that they were mine.
我努力把整理庭院的原因
I wanted to think the reason I started working on my yard...
想的跟布莱斯无关
...had nothing to do with Bryce.
只是为了美化住宅
It was about making our house better.
既然他那样处理鸡蛋
After what he did with the eggs,
我又何必在意他想什么
why should I care what he thought about anything?
但我还是在意了
But I did.
你是在做修剪还是想把它劈死啊
Are you pruning that or trying to hack it to death?
我叫切特·邓肯  布莱斯的外公
Hi. I'm Chet Duncan, Bryce's grandfather.
很抱歉这么晚才过来自我介绍
Sorry it's taken me so long to come over and introduce myself.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
你是想把枝修剪得一样高吗
So are you trimming all these to the same height?
是啊  我是这么想的  就是不知道怎么做
Well, yeah, that's what I was thinking, but I don't know.
如果把它们全除了  你觉得会更好些吗
Do you think it would look better to take them out?
这些是红豆杉灌木  修剪好了会很棒的
Oh, these are Hicksii shrubs. These will prune up nicely.
邓肯先生
Listen, Mr. Duncan.
叫我切特就行
Call me Chet.
切特
Chet.
如果你是因为布莱斯说的话才过来的
If you're here because of what Bryce said...
我不需要你来帮忙
...I don't need your help.
我在报纸上读到过你的消息
Read about you in the paper.
要是瑞妮在一定会跟你坐树上的
Renee would've sat up in that tree with you.
她会在树上呆上一整夜
She would've sat up there all night.
瑞妮
Renee?
我妻子
My wife.
你让我想起了她
You remind me a lot of her.
我们在院子里忙活了几周
We worked on the yard for weeks.
边干活边聊天
And the whole time we worked, we talked.
-就这儿吗  -对  很好
- Right there? - Perfect, yeah.
他想了解更多有关梧桐树的事
He wanted to know more about the sycamore tree.
他非常清楚
He knew exactly what it meant...
所谓整体大于部分之和的含义
...about the whole being greater than the sum of its parts.
他说人也是一样
He said it was the same with people...
只不过对于人  整体有时反而更小
...but sometimes with people, the whole could be less.
我觉得这很有意思
I thought that was pretty interesting.
我开始观察那些从小学就认识的人
I started looking at people i'd known since elementary school...
想看看他们
...trying to figure out if they
是大于还是小于各自的部分之和
were more or less than the sum of their parts.
切特说得对  很多人作为整体反而更小
Chet was right. A lot of them were less.
在所有同学里
Of all my classmates,
我唯一不确定的就是布莱斯
the one person I couldn't seem to place was Bryce.
要是以前  我会毫无疑问地说
Until recently, I would've said with absolute certainty...
作为整体他远比他的部分之和要大
...that he was greater, far greater, than the sum of his parts.
现在我却不那么确定了
But now I wasn't so sure.
看上去不错  朱莉  干得好
It's looking good, Juli. Nice job.
谢了  大部分都是切特做的
Thanks. Chet did most of it.
我为我的行为道歉
I'm sorry for what I did.
我就是不明白  布莱斯
I just don't get it, Bryce.
干嘛不直接告诉我
Why didn't you just tell me?
他真有歉意吗
Was he really sorry?
还是说了这些话他自己会好受些呢
Or was he just saying these things to make himself feel better?
或许我只是希望他的整体比部分之和大吧
Then I thought maybe I just wanted him to be more than the sum of his parts.
但当我看着他的眼睛
But as I looked into his eyes...
那双明亮迷人的眼睛
...those dazzling eyes...
我第一次确定布莱斯作为整体一定更小
...for the first time I was pretty sure that Bryce Loski was less.
我们要请贝克家过来吃饭
We're going to invite the Bakers over for dinner.
-什么  -有点意外啊  妈妈
- What? - I don't know, Mom.
这是个很棒的主意
I think that's a marvelous idea.
帕茜  干嘛请他们来
Patsy, what purpose does this serve?
翠娜·贝克人很不错
Trina Baker is a very nice person.
-马特跟马克也很酷  -我讨厌酷
- And Matt and Mark are really cool. - I hate cool.
几年前就该请他们吃饭了
Something we should've done years ago.
是啊  当初没有  现在就更不行了
Yeah, but we didn't. And now we can't.
时机已经错过了
The statute of limitations has run out.
请贝克家过来吃饭请定了
We're having the Bakers over for dinner.
如果是因为昨晚我所说的话  我道歉  好吗
If this is about what I said last night, I'm sorry, okay?
可是请他们过来吃饭也治不好他弟弟
But, you know, having them over for dinner is not gonna fix his brother.
这将是个正式晚宴
It's going to be a sit-down dinner.
希望大家衣着得体
And I expect everyone to dress accordingly.
天哪  就弄个烧烤不好吗
Oh, God. Can't we just have a barbecue?
是正式晚宴
It's going to be a sit-down dinner.
杀了我吧
Just shoot me now.
这话可不能乱说
Careful what you wish for.
于是就这么定了
So that was it.
正式着装的正式晚宴
A dress-up, sit-down dinner
不久就要和朱莉·贝克坐在一个饭桌上了
with Juli Baker was in my immediate future.
这让我在学校看见朱莉时更不自然了
And that made seeing Juli at school more uncomfortable.
我不知不觉中在课堂上盯着她看
I found myself staring at her in class.
她的长发散落至肩
And the way her hair fell back over her shoulders...
看上去就像她在报纸图片里的样子
...she looked just like the picture in the newspaper.
丹娜·崔斯勒发现了我的痴样
Dana Tressler caught me watching.
要是我反应慢点的话  又得风言风语了
If I didn't do something fast, this could spread like wildfire.
她头发上有只蜜蜂
There was a bee in her hair.
看  飞走了
See, there it goes.
根本没蜜蜂
There's no bee.
从窗户飞出去了
It flew out the window.
我总算躲过了一劫
I convinced myself I'd dodged a bullet.
我不能再这么想着朱莉了
I had to put Juli out of my mind.
还是把注意力集中到重要的学业上来吧
Keep the focus on the important stuff like schoolwork.
我却总是身不由己
My weakness was unnerving.
借卷笔刀一用
I need your sharpener.
进来要敲门
You ever heard of knocking?
藏着什么呢  老爸的《花花公子》杂志吗
Hey, what you got there? Dad's Playboy?
不关你事
None of your business.
-代我向十月女郎问好哦  -出去
- Give my best to Miss October. - Get out.
-应该说是代你自己向她问好吧  -你真恶心
- Or should I say your best? Ha, ha. - You're disgusting.
又躲过一劫
Another disaster avoided.
我的生活俨然成了雷区
My life had become a minefield.
-嘿  哥们  -嗨
- Hey, man. - Hey.
这是什么啊
What's this?
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
好吧  如你所想  不过我可以解释
Okay, it is what you think, but I can explain.
好吧  我解释不了  待会再说行吗
Okay, I can't explain. Can we just talk about it later?
随便你了
Whatever you say.
我得找个人说说心事
I had to talk to someone.
不如就找伽利特吧
Why not Garrett?
或许他能帮我重回正轨
Maybe he could help me get back on track.
在内心情感方面伽利特极有悟性
Garrett was surprisingly sensitive in matters of the heart.
你神经病啊  朱莉·贝克  你讨厌她
Are you freaking mental? Juli Baker. You hate her.
我也奇怪  我好像并不讨厌她了
That's what's weird. I don't think I do.
我就是忍不住老想她
I can't stop thinking about her.
-你完了  -那我该怎么办
- You got it bad, man. - Well, what do I do?
你必须及早打消这种想法
Well, you gotta nip this in the bud.
这不是真实的情感
These aren't real emotions.
-不是吗  -你是因为鸡蛋的事而感觉愧疚
- They're not? - You feel guilty because of the egg thing.
是啊  我还侮辱了她家的院子
Yeah, and I insulted her yard.
没错  不过那地方确实一团糟
Exactly. Of course, the place is a dump anyways.
她有个智障的叔叔
Her dad's got a retarded brother
家里的钱都花在他身上了
and all their money goes to helping him.
智障   靠  那你就该明白了
A retard? Well, shoot, that ought to tell you something.
-明白什么  -朱莉啊
- About what? - About Juli.
什么啊
What are you saying?
所谓上梁不正下梁歪  朋友
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, my friend.
真让人受不了  我真想朝他大吼
I couldn't believe it. I wanted to yell at him.
告诉他他并不了解朱莉
Tell him that he didn't know Juli like I did.
但最终说出口的却是:
But all that came out was:
哦  对哦
Heh, oh. Right.
对吧
Yeah.
没错  嗯...回头再聊吧
Right. Um, I'll talk to you later.
放学后我本该去伽利特那儿的
I was supposed to go to Garrett's after school...
可我不想见他
...but I couldn't be around him.
他太过分了
He'd crossed the line.
跟他一样过分的还有我爸
And standing right next to him across that line was my father.
我才不管他们想什么
I didn't care what they thought.
我喜欢朱莉·贝克
I liked Juli Baker.
每个周日早上我们家都很宁静
Sunday mornings are peaceful in our house.
爸爸睡懒觉
My dad lets himself sleep in.
我妈也不做早饭
My mother lets herself not fix breakfast.
要是哥哥们前一天出去和乐队玩到很晚
If my brothers have been out late playing with their band...
他们到中午才会起床
...you won't even know they're around till noon.
不过这个周日  我醒来后有种奇怪的感觉
But this Sunday, I woke up feeling weird.
我必须得忙活些什么
I had to do something
好让自己忘掉对布莱斯纠结的感觉
to shake off the confused feelings about Bryce...
这些感觉又开始萦绕在我脑中了
...that were starting to creep back in.
你还真做到了  不是吗
You really did it, didn't you? Heh.
-为你骄傲  -谢谢爸爸
- Proud of you. - Thanks, Dad.
-你去哪儿  -去看看丹尼  今天是他生日
- Where you going? - To see Daniel. It's his birthday.
我想跟你一起去
I wanna come with you.
亲爱的  好好享受早晨吧  陪陪你妈
Oh, honey, just enjoy the morning, stay with your mom.
不  爸  我想去
No, Dad. I wanna come.
甜心  听着
Sweetheart, listen.
有时侯丹尼...
Sometimes, with Daniel...
我要去  爸
I'm coming, Dad.
好吧
Okay.
最好留个便条给你妈妈
We'd better leave a note for your mother.
这些年来我都没去见过我叔叔丹尼
In all the years, I'd never visited my Uncle Daniel.
不知道为什么
I don't know why.
这事一直都是我爸单独去做的
It was always something my dad did alone.
去德文霍斯特的路上我们少言寡语
We didn't say much to each other on the drive to Devonhurst,
但我并不介意
but I didn't care.
我就是喜欢跟我爸呆在一起
I just liked being with my dad.
不过似乎一路上的沉默
Somehow the silence seemed to connect us
反而胜过了千言万语
in a way that words never could.
这里的人把劳动也当做一种治疗手段
The residents tend to the grounds as part of their therapy.
得花点时间才能适应  不过他们人都很好
It takes some getting used to. They're good people, though.
丹尼
Daniel?
Daniel.
理查德  你来啦
Richard! You're here!
理查德来给我过生日了
Richard for my birthday.
谁  理查德  这是谁
Who? Richard, who? Who?
谁  谁  理查德  这是谁  谁
Who? Who? Richard, who? Who?
丹尼  丹尼  这是朱莉安娜  我女儿
Daniel, Daniel, it's Julianna. It's my daughter.
你的侄女
Your niece.
朱莉安娜
Julianna.
-朱莉安娜  -生日快乐  丹尼叔叔
- Ha, Julianna. - Happy birthday, Uncle Daniel.
理查德  今天是我生日
Richard. It's my birthday.
我有你照片  朱莉安娜  我有你照片
I have your pictures, Julianna. I have your pictures.
我们给你准备了礼物
We have a present for you.
拼图吗  拼图  理查德
A puzzle? A puzzle, Richard?
不只拼图
Not just a puzzle.
拼图和一个...
A puzzle and a...
风车
...pinwheel.
风车  谢谢  理查德
A pinwheel! Thank you, Richard.
嗯
Yes.
橙色的  出去吗  出去  理查德
Orange. Outside? Outside, Richard?
想出去吗  好吧  那就去麦艾乐
You wanna go outside? All right, we'll go to, uh, McElliot's.
-我们走到那边买个冰激凌  -冰激凌
- We'll walk out there for an ice cream. - Ice cream!
不  不  不  不行
Oh, no. No, no, we can't.
丹尼不喜欢冰激凌
Daniel doesn't like ice cream.
-我喜欢冰激凌啊  理查德  -我开玩笑呢
- I do like ice cream, Richard. - I'm only kidding.
我知道你喜欢
I know you like ice cream.
你喜欢冰激凌  好了  走吧
You love ice cream. All right, come on.
麦艾乐冰激凌糖果店
给  拿好
Here you go. Got it?
给你
Here you go.
今天是我生日
It's my birthday.
棒棒糖  今天是我生日
Lollipop. It's my birthday.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
好了  丹尼  等等
All right, Daniel. Okay, wait, wait.
冰激凌  冰激凌
Ice cream. Ice cream.
-我的冰激凌  我的冰激凌  -没事的  丹尼
- My ice cream. My ice cream. - It's okay. Daniel.
丹尼
Daniel!
丹尼  别要了  我再...
Daniel! Leave it, I'll get y...
掉地上了  冰激凌掉地上了
Ice cream on the floor. Ice cream on the floor.
-你再去给他买一个  -好
- Would you go get him another cone? - Yeah.
我要冰激凌  理查德
I need ice cream, Richard!
今天我生日  理查德  我生日
It's my birthday, Richard. It's my birthday!
冰激凌  理查德  冰激凌  理查德
Ice cream, Richard! Ice cream, Richard!
停  停
Stop! Stop it!
-我要  -行了  停手
- I need it! - Stop it! Stop it!
-来了  -冰激凌
- Here we go. - Ice cream!
-理查德  -好了好了  有冰激凌了
- Richard! - Okay, okay. I've got some ice cream.
生日冰激凌  太好了  理查德
Birthday ice cream. That's good, Richard.
抱歉  他以前没这样过...
I'm so sorry. He hasn't done anything like that...
我经常听爸爸说丹尼的生活有多么不易
I'd often heard my father talk about how difficult life was for Daniel.
到今天我才真正理解
But I never really understood it until now.
-嗯  转得不错  -橙色的
- Yeah, there you go. - Heh. Orange.
走回去的时候  丹尼跟没事一样
On the walk back, Daniel acted like nothing had happened.
这边  这边
Other way. Other way.
回家的路上  爸爸告诉我
On the ride home, my dad told me that
在生我们之前  叔叔跟他和妈妈一起生活
Uncle Daniel used to live with him and Mom before we were born.
后来就变得很困难了
But after a while, it became too difficult.
回家后  表面看来一切如常
When we got home, everything looked the same.
可实际上却变了
But it wasn't.
在此之前  丹尼对我来说只是个名字
Before today, Daniel had always been just a name to me.
现在却是家庭的一部分了
Now he was part of the family.
怎么样
How'd it go?
很高兴我去了
I'm glad I went.
我也很高兴
I'm glad you went too.
翠娜  今天周日  干嘛要拖地啊
Trina, it's Sunday. What are you doing mopping the floor?
帕茜·洛斯奇请我们下周五去她家吃晚饭
Patty Loski invited us over for dinner Friday night.
那不是应该她拖她家的地吗
Shouldn't she be mopping her floor?
难道是要借咱家地板一用
Or did she ask to borrow ours?
我就是有点激动
Nervous energy.
-请我们全家吗  -嗯  全家
- Did she invite all of us? - Yes, she did.
甚至包括我们的沙门氏菌朋友吗
Even our friend Sal Monella?
理查德
Richard.
为什么  都这么多年了
Why, after all these years?
她说这么多年都没邀请过我们  很过意不去
Well, she said she felt really bad that they hadn't invited us before...
而且看来他们也想和我们加深了解
...and apparently they want to get to know us better.
你想去吗
And you wanna go?
她坚持要请
Well, she insisted.
我觉得这也挺不错的
And I think it would be really nice.
好吧
All right.
那就去吧
We'll go.
我不太想去洛斯奇家吃饭
I wasn't too thrilled about dinner with the Loskis...
但我看得出我妈很期待
...but I could see it meant a lot to my mother.
第二天上学时  我总是走神
At school the next day, I couldn't seem to concentrate.
思绪总是跑到丹尼那边
My thoughts kept running back to Daniel.
爷爷奶奶一定为这样的儿子付出了很多
I wondered what my grandparents had gone through having a son like him...
这时现实却打乱了我的思绪
...when reality interrupted.
-布莱斯·洛斯奇喜欢你  -什么
- Bryce Loski likes you. - What?
他非常迷恋你
He's got a big crush on you.
你说什么啊
What are you talking about?
布莱斯·洛斯奇才没有迷恋我
Bryce Loski does not have a crush on me.
是吗  科学课的时候  我发现他盯着你看
Oh, yeah? In science, I caught him staring at you.
她说你头发上有只蜜蜂
He said it was because there was a bee in your hair.
这理由真是太逊了
Is that the lamest cover-up or what?
或许真有蜜蜂呢
Maybe there was a bee.
你吸引的是只叫布莱斯的蜜蜂吧
The only bee you're attracting is B-R-Y-C-E.
我告诉你  这男孩已经坠入情网了
I'm telling you, that boy is lost in love land.
-跟我来  -去哪儿
- Come on. - Where?
我看见他跟伽利特偷偷溜到那边去了  来
I saw him sneaking off with Garrett. Come on.
你神经病啊  朱莉·贝克  你讨厌她
Are you freaking mental? Juli Baker. You hate her.
我也奇怪  我好像并不讨厌她了
That's what's so weird. I don't think I do.
我就是忍不住老想她
I can't stop thinking about her.
-你完了  -那我该怎么办
- You got it bad, man. - What do I do?
你得趁早打消这种想法
You gotta nip this in the bud.
-这不是真实的情感  -不是吗
- These aren't real emotions. - They're not?
你是因为鸡蛋的事情而感觉愧疚
You feel guilty because of the egg thing.
是啊  我还侮辱了她家的院子
Yeah, and I insulted her yard.
没错  那地方确实一团糟
Exactly. The place is a dump anyways.
她有个智障的叔叔
Her dad's got a retarded brother
家里的钱都花在他身上了
and all their money goes to helping him.
智障   那你就该明白了
A retard? Well, that ought to tell you something.
-明白什么  -朱莉啊
- About what? - About Juli.
什么啊
What are you saying?
所谓上梁不正下梁歪  朋友
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, my friend.
-哦  对哦  -对吧
- Oh, heh. Yeah. Right. - Yeah.
回头再聊吧
I'll talk to you later.
好的
Okay.
抱歉  我还以为...
I'm sorry. I thought...
没关系  没事的
It's okay. It's fine.
确实无所谓
And it was.
现在我的困惑已经烟消云散了
Because now my confusion was gone.
我确定  我已经不再喜欢布莱斯·洛斯奇了
I was sure I no longer liked Bryce Loski.
妈  你搞成这样是想让贝克家相形见绌吗
Mom, are you trying to make the Bakers feel totally worthless?
我就是想弄丰盛点
I want it to be nice.
-你怎么还不穿好衣服  -我这就去
- And why aren't you dressed? - I'm going.
我想让朱莉觉得我很帅
I wanted to look good for Juli.
但又不能让她看出我是特意为她而打扮的
But I didn't want her to think that I wanted to look good for her.
这两者有着微妙的界限
It was a fine line.
非常微妙的界限
A very fine line.
布莱斯  他们到了  快下来
Bryce, they're here. Come on down.
来了
Coming!
快进来
Come on in.
-请进  请进  -真漂亮
- Come in, come in. - There goes the waistline.
很高兴你们能来  琳妮塔  斯蒂文  客人们到了
I'm glad you could make it. Lynetta, Steven, company's here.
-来了  -这是什么  自己做的馅饼吗
- Coming! - What is this? Homemade pie?
对  核桃馅饼和蓝莓芝士馅饼
Yes, it's pecan and blueberry cheesecake.
我们拿到厨房去吧
Let's take them to the kitchen.
-大家好  -你好  好漂亮啊
- Hi, guys. - Hey, looking good.
-这是我爸  -你好  我是琳妮塔
- This is my dad. - Hi, I'm Lynetta.
你好  很高兴终于见到你了
Hi, nice to finally meet you.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you too.
-我儿子们一直跟我说...  -你好  大个子
- My boys are telling me that... - Hey, big guy.
你好  斯蒂文  最近还好吧
Hey, Steven. How are you?
早就该一起吃个饭了  快进来
We should've done this a long time ago. Come on in.
你们家可真漂亮啊
This is a cool place.
嗯  还凑合吧  来  我带你们去看我的房间
Yeah, it's all right. Come on, I'll show you my room.
你该听听我们写的新歌
You gotta hear this new song we wrote.
特好听
It's so good.
你好
Hi.
你真漂亮
You look nice.
我在图书馆听到你和伽利特取笑我叔叔
I heard you and Garrett making fun of my uncle in the library.
我不想和你说话
And I don't wanna speak to you.
现在不想  永远不想
Not now, not ever.
-我认为可以  -不过你的建议
- And I say you can. - But what you're proposing
需要一个永动机  所以不太可能
would require a perpetual-motion machine, so it's not possible.
如果有两个相反磁极和一个不带磁的导体...
If you had two opposite charged poles with a neutral conductor...
永动机
Perpetual motion?
此刻我的心都要碎了
Here I was, dying inside,
他们却在谈论永动机
and they were talking about perpetual motion.
朱莉是怎么知道那些玩意的
And how did Juli know about all that stuff?
快来  同志们  饭好了  琳妮塔
Come on, everybody, dinner's ready. Lynetta!
吃饭了
Dinner!
朱莉  能和你说几句话吗
Juli, can I talk to you?
伽利特说的话是错的  我知道
It was wrong, what Garrett said. I know it.
他说的时候你就知道是错的吗
Did you know it was wrong when he said it?
对  我想揍他来的
Yeah. I wanted to punch him.
但当时是在图书馆里
But we were in the library.
所以你就赞同了他说的话  还和他一起笑
So instead you just agreed with him and laughed.
嗯
Yeah.
那你就是个懦夫
Then that makes you a coward.
吃饭时我不得不和朱莉坐对面
I had to sit across from Juli for an entire dinner.
我老爸是对的
My dad was right.
本该吃烧烤的
We should have barbecued.
你们能和我们一起吃饭真是太棒了
I just want to say how wonderful it is to have you share a meal with us.
希望以后能经常一起吃
May it be the first of many.
呛到了
Wrong pipe.
我们太开心了
We couldn't be happier.
我们能来拜访真的很激动
We are just all so thrilled to be here.
朱莉  你的院子收拾得真不错
Juli, you did a really nice job on your yard.
谢谢  切特帮了不少忙
Thanks. Chet was a big help.
对  我知道
Yeah, I know.
你得告诉我你的秘诀
You gotta tell me your secret.
在家我可指望不上他干一点活
I can't get him to do a thing around here.
-斯蒂文  -开个玩笑
- Steven. - I kid.
跟你们说  小区现在真的有了生气
I'm telling you, the neighborhood is really coming to life.
我是说  新房子已经建的差不多了
I mean, that new house is taking shape.
哪个
Which one?
就是那棵被砍掉的难看的大树那里
You know, the one where they cut down that big ugly tree.
我本想说很多人都喜欢那棵树
I wanted to say that a lot of people liked that tree,
可我没说出口
but I didn't.
我不想顶撞我老爸
I didn't want to go against my dad.
有些人觉得那棵树可是小区的宝贝
Some people thought that tree was the jewel of the neighborhood.
对  品味不行没办法
Yeah, there's no accounting for taste.
那么  马特  马克  马克  马特
So, Matt, Mark, Mark, Matt...
你们马上就毕业了  是吗
You guys are gonna be graduating soon, huh?
对  谢天谢地
Yeah, thank God.
你们不喜欢高中吗
You don't like high school?
-开玩笑吧  -不
- You kidding? - No.
高中是我一生中最美好的时光
High school was the best time of my life.
-对我们来说不是的  -对  我们可受够了
- Not for us, no. - Yeah, we've had enough of that scene.
那就更别提大学了  是吧
So college is probably out of the question, huh?
不  大学有可能
No, it's a possibility.
实际上他们已经被几所大学录取了
They've actually been accepted at several places already.
对  是这样
Yes, they have.
是吗
Really?
不错嘛
That's good.
不过  我们打算先尝试一下做音乐
But, we're gonna give music a shot first.
-是吗  -他们很有天赋的
- Really? - They are very talented.
他们的乐队真的很棒
Their band is really boss.
他们录了一堆样带  非常不错
They did a bunch of demos and they're really cool.
谢谢  琳
Thanks, Lyn.
我和斯蒂文刚认识时  他也在乐队
When Steven and I first met, he was playing in a band.
你以前在乐队演奏过吗
You played in a band?
他是个超棒的萨克斯手
He was a wonderful saxophone player.
-酷啊  你还演奏吗  -我...
- Cool. You still play? -  I...
你愿意的话  有空可以来和我们一起演奏
If you want, you can come jam out with us sometime.
嗯  你们...
Ah, you...
不  我是说...
No, I mean...
我已经不玩那个了
That's not me anymore.
你们在观众面前表演过吗
Have you boys ever performed in front of an audience?
经常
A lot of times.
马特和马克越是谈论他们的音乐事业
The more Matt and Mark talked about their musical exploits,
我老爸就越沉默
the quieter my dad got.
他时不时想挤出点笑容
He tried to plaster on a smile now and then,
不过他心里好像很伤感
but underneath he seemed really sad.
但是我父母开始还不喜欢他
But my parents didn't like him at first.
共和党拼命抵制新政
Republicans fought like crazy against the New Deal.
那晚剩下的时间过得还算风平浪静
The rest of the evening was painless enough.
不过整晚朱莉都没和我说一句话
But through it all, Juli didn't say a word to me.
甚至没看过我一眼
Never even looked at me.
直到她快走时
Until she was about to leave.
对不起我刚来时发这么大脾气
I'm sorry I was so angry when we first came in.
我觉得今晚每个人都挺开心
I think everyone had a good time.
很感谢你妈妈邀请我们
Your mom was really nice to invite us.
再见
See you.
她的道歉让我感觉更糟
Her apology made things worse.
-等等我  -我知道她并没有原谅我
- Wait for me. - I knew I wasn't forgiven.
她似乎根本不屑于对我怀恨在心
It was like I wasn't even important enough to hold a grudge against.
我觉得他们一家很讨人喜欢
I think they're a delightful family.
两个男孩和我想象的很不一样
Those boys were nothing like I expected.
我认为他们是很不错的年轻人
I thought they were very nice young men.
-俩小痞子  -什么
- Hoodlums. - What?
你觉得他们付得起那些录音设备的钱吗
How you think they can afford all that recording gear?
斯蒂文  拜托  你不能这样乱说人家
Steven, please. You can't just make an accusation like that.
别那么天真  帕茜
Don't be so naive, Patsy.
你知道录制样带有多贵吗
Do you know how expensive it is to record a demo?
他们说不定在偷轮毂罩卖钱
They're probably stealing hubcaps, for chrissake.
你真是个混蛋
You are such an asshole.
你发什么疯
What is the matter with you?
去死吧
Go to hell.
别这样跟我说话
Don't you talk to me like that.
斯蒂文  站住
Steven, stop!
在这家里没人能和我这样说话  -站住
Nobody talks to me like that in my own house! - Stop!
以前我见过老爸生气  可这次不同
I'd seen my father angry before, but this was different.
那晚我躺在床上
As I lay in bed that night...
思索着我老爸为什么总看不起贝克一家
I thought about how my dad always looked down on the Bakers.
他还称他们是垃圾
And how he'd called them trash
还取笑贝克先生画的画
and made fun of Mr. Baker's paintings.
现在我知道了  他只是在生自己的气
And now I realized he was just mad at himself.
可为什么呢
But why?
朱莉叫我懦夫
Juli called me a coward.
我老爸会不会也是个懦夫呢
Was it possible my dad was a coward too?
不知道
I didn't know.
那又怎样呢
What difference did it make?
朱莉·贝克走出了我的生活
Juli Baker was out of my life.
或者  更准确地说
Or, more accurately...
我走出了她的生活
I was out of hers.
当我为参加洛斯奇家的晚宴换衣服时
As I was getting dressed for the Loskis' dinner party
我不由地注视着爸爸送我的那幅画
I found myself staring at the painting my father had given me
又一次怒不可遏
and became furious all over again.
布莱斯从来都不是我的朋友  从来不是
Bryce had never been a friend to me, ever.
砍树时  他不站在我这边
He hadn't taken my side about the tree;
他扔了我的鸡蛋
he'd thrown away my eggs;
还取笑我叔叔的花费
and he made fun of me at my uncle's expense.
当妈妈叫我该走了的时候
When my mother called that it was time to go...
朱莉  我们走吧  迟到了
Juli, let's go, we're late!
我非常想冲出去告诉她
I went out with every intention of telling her
我不去洛斯奇家吃饭
that I wasn't going to the Loskis for dinner.
亲爱的  帮我拿着这些
Honey, please hold these.
我得赶紧再看看我的头发
I need to check my hair really quickly one more time.
-亲爱的  你的头发很漂亮  -真的吗
- Honey, your hair is perfect. - Really?
但是她看起来那么开心
But she looked so happy
她还花了那么多功夫做馅饼
and she'd gone to so much trouble over the pies
我不能扫她的兴
that I couldn't.
天啊  老天  差一点
My gosh. God, what a disaster.
好啦  给  端着  你端着这盘
Okay. Here, hold one, and you hold this.
-我不想端  -我不会让你端的
- I don't wanna hold it. - I won't have you hold it.
我们走吧  小伙子们
Let's go, boys.
但那并不意味着我得对布莱斯客气
But that didn't mean I had to be nice to Bryce.
我不想跟你说话
And I don't wanna speak to you.
现在不想  永远不想
Not now, not ever.
掌握主动权的感觉不错
It felt good to take charge.
我感到强大自信
I felt strong, in control.
我告诉了布莱斯我的想法
I told Bryce what I thought
还决定那天晚上不再和他讲话
and I was determined not to talk to him for the rest of the evening.
晚饭时让我惊讶的是
At dinner it struck me that
我们在和一群陌生人共同进餐
we were sharing a meal with a group of strangers.
我们住在洛斯奇家对面已经好多年了
We'd lived across the street from the Loskis for years
但是除了切特  我根本就不认识这些人
but except for Chet, I didn't know these people at all.
洛斯奇先生外表温文尔雅
Mr. Loski was clean and smooth on the outside...
但貌似也只不过是
but it seemed like
金玉其外败絮其中
there was something rotten buried just beneath the surface.
到晚饭结束时  我只感到平静超脱
By the end of the evening, all I felt was detached, neutral.
没有激烈言辞  也没觉得余怒未消
No fireworks, no leftover anger,
更没有心烦意乱  什么也没有
no flutters, nothing.
再见
See you.
那晚我入睡前觉得很平静
I went to bed that night feeling peaceful.
-你还好吧  -还好
- You okay? - Yeah.
有这样的家人我很知足
I was grateful that I had the family I had.
不再关注布莱斯·洛斯奇  也让我感觉挺好
And it felt good to no longer care about Bryce Loski.
和贝克一家的晚餐  让我付出了代价
The dinner with the Bakers had taken its toll on me.
一年一度的校园筹款活动开始了
Then the annual school fundraiser arrived
梅菲德中学年度筹款义拍会  1963年"午餐男孩"名单
我发现自己被一系列新的问题纠缠住了
and I found myself with a whole new set of problems.
我成了"午餐男孩"
I was a Basketboy.
9号  布莱斯·洛斯奇
要想充分理解作为"午餐男孩"的耻辱
To fully appreciate the humiliation of being a Basketboy,
你就得知道  被选中的可怜蛋
you need to know that the chosen few
要在学校同学面前被拍卖
are auctioned off in front of the student body
卖给出价最高的女同学
to the highest-bidding females.
对  形式上我们是拎着装午餐的篮子登台
Yes, technically, each of us comes with a lunch in a basket.
不过还是不要自欺欺人了
But let's not kid ourselves.
其实就是出卖男色
This was a beefcake parade.
他在这里  我的偶像
There he is, my idol.
再胡说你就死定了
One word, you're a dead man.
不  老兄  说真的  你不会相信的
No, man, I'm serious. Listen, you won't believe this.
什么
What?
两个辣妹为你大打出手
Two of the hottest chicks are fighting over you.
-你在说什么啊  -雪莉和米胖分手了
- What are you talking about? - Sherry is breaking up with Mitch.
她和美兰妮为你大打竞价之战
She and Melanie are having a bidding war over you.
没兴趣
I don't care.
你是傻瓜吗  雪莉为了你把米胖甩了
Are you nuts? Sherry dumped Mitch because of you.
你是我的偶像
You're my idol.
即便成了伽利特的偶像
As comforting as it was to be Garrett's idol,
成为9号"午餐男孩"的恐惧心情也丝毫未减
it didn't diminish the horror of being Basketboy number nine.
我唯一的希望是
And my only hope was that
一场巨大的龙卷风在活动举办前光临学校
a giant tornado would destroy the school before the big event.
但这很渺茫
It was a long shot.
欢迎大家
Welcome everyone
光临今年的梅菲德中学筹款义拍会
to this year's Mayfield Boosters Club Auction.
让我们再次有请
Once again we are pleased to present
-梅菲德中学的二十位杰出青年...  -布莱斯  布莱斯
- 20 of Mayfield's finest young men... - Bryce, Bryce, Bryce.
-你到这来做什么  -朱莉在第三排
- What are you doing here? - Juli's in the third row.
-那又怎样  -她手持巨款
- So? - So she's got a wad of cash.
-放屁  -是真屁
- Bullshit. - Bull-true.
我看到她在柜子旁数钱来的
I saw her counting it by her locker.
现在
And now
请在场的梅菲德中学师生热烈欢迎
please give a big Mayfield School welcome...
1963年度的"午餐男孩"们
to your 1963 Basketboys.
朱莉带着钱  这是什么意思
Juli with cash? What did this mean?
会不会是她想拍下我
Was it possible she was gonna bid on me?
首先  我们有请
First up, we have
雷蒙·休斯
Raymond Hughes.
雷蒙是象棋小组成员
Raymond's on the chess team
他爱好集邮和玩溜溜球
and his hobbies include stamp collecting and the yo-yo.
记住  竞价成功后
Remember, when you bid
你得到的不只是英俊的休斯先生
you'll not only be getting the handsome Mr. Hughes.
还可以享用到
You'll also be enjoying
美味的鸡肉沙拉三明治
a lovely chicken-salad sandwich
配有美味蘸料  看上去是豆酱  还有...
and what looks to be a tasty bean dip, and...
抱歉  是洋葱酱
Excuse me, onion dip.
还有一大块樱桃馅饼
And a big slice of cherry pie.
好  起价五美元  有谁愿意出
Okay, who will start the bidding at $5?
-竞拍就这样开始了  -有人吗
- Thus began the bidding. - Anybody?
或者说  是从雷蒙·休斯的险些流拍开始了
Or in Raymond Hughes' case, the lack of bidding.
很好  成交
Very good, here we go.
-五美元  -成交
- Five. - Sold.
-十美元  -成交
- Ten dollars. - Sold.
-十五块  -成交
- Fifteen. - Sold.
快  是不是有出十块的
Come on. Do I hear 10?
-十块  -十块
- Ten. - Ten.
-十块  -是花生酱香蕉三明治哟
- Ten. - Peanut-butter-and-banana sandwich.
十五块
Fifteen.
十五美元成交
Sold for $15.
8号是艾迪·楚勒
Number eight is Eddie Trulock.
艾迪是辩论队的成员
Eddie is a member of the debate team.
艾迪·楚勒之后就要轮到我登台了
Now only Eddie Trulock stood between me and the auction block.
我可没有兴趣听他的爱好和篮子里有什么
I wasn't interested in his hobbies or what was in his basket.
我们从五美元开始
Let's start the bidding at $5.
我的脑子里只有朱莉
All I could think of was Juli.
-有人出价吗  -万一她真对我出价了怎么办
- Anybody? - What if she did bid on me?
万一她跟雪莉和美兰妮展开竞价大战
What if she got in a bidding war
最后输掉了怎么办
with Sherry and Melanie and lost out?
没人出价吗
No bidders?
我正在沉思这个恐怖情景  突然听到...
I was contemplating the horrors of this scenario when...
八美元
Eight dollars.
有人出价了  八美元
There you go. Eight dollars,
这个价还差不多  有没有出十美元的
that's more like it. Do I hear 10?
朱莉·贝克为艾迪·楚勒出价
Juli Baker was bidding on Eddie Trulock?
-好  八美元一次  -她怎么会为艾迪出价
- Okay, 8 going once. - How could she bid on Eddie?
-八美元两次  -她怎么会出价竞拍别人呢
- Eight going twice. - How could she bid on anyone?
卖给朱莉·贝克啦
Sold to Juli Baker.
下一个是9号"午餐男孩"  布莱斯·洛斯奇
Next is Basketboy number nine, Bryce Loski.
我知道该走上前去  可是我动不了
I knew I was supposed to step forward, but I couldn't move.
前面来  布莱斯  不要害羞
Step up, Bryce, don't be shy.
姗姗来迟总比没来好
Better late than never.
布莱斯喜欢打棒球
Bryce likes to play baseball.
-五美元  -先等我...
- Five dollars. - Wait until l...
-十美元
- Ten.
好吧  貌似竞价已经开始了
Well, it appears the bidding is underway.
-十五美元  -二十
- Fifteen. - Twenty.
-二十五  -三十
- Twenty-five. - Thirty.
-三十五  -四十
- Thirty-five. - Forty.
-五十  -天哪
- Fifty. - Oh, my...
五十美元
Fifty dollars.
五十美元一次
Fifty going once.
五十美元两次
Fifty going twice.
五十美元卖给雪莉·斯图小姐了
Sold to Miss Sherry Stalls for $50.
打破义拍会记录了
An all-time record.
筹款会将会非常感谢如此慷慨的捐助
The boosters will be very grateful for such a generous donation.
真奇怪
It's strange.
我在这里和全校最火辣的女孩共进午餐
Here I was having lunch with the hottest girl in school
我却觉得很悲惨
and I was miserable.
我们打算去湖边   我爸爸在那有个小木屋
We're going up to the lake. My dad has a cabin there.
在那儿能把皮肤晒得黝黑
And you get the most outrageous tan.
因为朱莉就坐在离我不到二十英尺的地方
Because less than 20 feet away from me was Juli.
我的朱莉和艾迪·楚勒在一起
My Juli with Eddie Trulock.
她笑着
She's laughing.
她在笑什么
What was she laughing about?
她怎么能坐在那开怀大笑
How could she sit there and laugh
而且看起来这么漂亮呢
and look so beautiful?
布莱斯  你还好吗
Bryce, are you all right?
什么
What?
你看什么呢
What are you staring at?
没什么
Nothing.
午餐真的很好吃  布莱斯
Lunch is really delicious, Bryce.
布莱斯  你听见我说话了吗
Bryce, did you hear me?
我说午餐真的很好吃
This is a really delicious lunch.
咱们别说什么晒黑和吃的了  好吗
Can we not talk about tans or food?
好啊  你想谈点什么
Well, what do you wanna talk about?
我也不知道  谈谈永动机怎样
I don't know, perpetual motion?
你知道这个吗
Do you know anything about that?
永什么
Perpetual what?
我不知道我当时怎么了
I don't know what came over me.
我好像是被附身了一样
It was like I was possessed or something.
-朱莉  我得和你谈谈  -什么
- Juli, I gotta talk to you. - What?
布莱斯  你怎么了
What's going on, Bryce?
你干什么啊
What are you doing?
布莱斯  别这样
Bryce, stop it.
布莱斯  你连一垒都没上啊
Bryce, you didn't even make it to first base.
我来亲你吧  哈哈
I'll kiss you. Ha, ha.
朱莉  朱莉
Juli! Juli!
朱莉  等等  我们能谈谈吗
Juli, wait. Can we talk?
朱莉
Juli!
-你是怎么了  -别管我  伽利特
- What's the matter with you? - Leave me alone, Garrett.
你本来在和校花约会
You get a date with the finest girl on campus
但是你却为了朱莉给搞砸了
and you blow it for Juli.
-你是不会懂的  -我确实一点都不懂
- You wouldn't understand! - I completely don't understand!
我们说的是朱莉·贝克啊
We're talking about Juli Baker here.
噩梦邻居  无所不知的讨厌鬼  鸡屎宝贝
Nightmare neighbor, know-it-all nuisance. The coop-poop babe.
你给我闭嘴
Shut up!
你是不是对她动心了  你怎么了
Hey, have you flipped? What's the matter with you?
你要是再这样的话
You know what, if you're gonna be like this,
咱们就别做朋友了
I don't need the association.
好啊  我不稀罕
Well, good, because neither do I.
是啊  我也不稀罕
Yeah, neither do I!
当我拎着一篮叮当作响的脏盘子走回家时
As I walked home with the dirty dishes clanking inside my picnic basket,
我满脑子都是朱莉
all I could think of was Juli.
我意识到伽利特至少有一件事说对了
And I realized Garrett was right about one thing:
我确实怦然心动了  彻彻底底的
I had flipped. Completely.
你好
Hello?
您好  贝克太太  朱莉在家吗
Oh, heh. Hi, Mrs. Baker. Is Juli there?
不好意思  布莱斯  朱莉不想说话
Oh. I'm sorry, Bryce. Juli doesn't wanna talk.
求您了  贝克太太  我得见她
Please, Mrs. Baker. I gotta see her.
我也没办法  布莱斯
I'm sorry, Bryce.
她把自己锁在屋子里了
But I'm afraid she's locked herself in her room.
那晚  我试着早点睡
I tried to go to bed early that night...
但就是无法入眠
but I couldn't sleep.
我在窗前坐了几个小时  呆望着她家的房子
I watched her house from my window for hours.
我必须找机会告诉她我的感受
I had to find a way to show her how I felt.
周一早晨  当我走进校门时
Monday morning, as I made my way into school...
我正琢磨着我想嫁给艾佛利兄弟[摇滚组合]中的哪个
I was deciding which of the Everly Brothers I'd rather marry...
这时丹娜·崔斯勒又让我想起了布莱斯
when Dana Tressler forced Bryce back into my brain.
朱莉  名单公布了
Juli. The list is out.
他榜上有名  9号  你的主菜
There he is, number nine, your main dish.
布莱斯·洛斯奇不是我的主菜
Bryce Loski's not my main dish.
哦  你在减肥吗
Oh, you're sticking to your diet.
这不是减肥  丹娜
It's not a diet, Dana.
-我已经不喜欢他了  -很高兴听你这么说
- I'm over him, okay? - I'm glad to hear it.
因为大家都说雪莉已经志在必得了
Because rumor has it Sherry's already staking her claim on him.
雪莉  雪莉·斯图吗
Sherry? Sherry Stalls?
丽兹  梅茜  名单出来了
Oh, Liz. Macy. The list is up.
那天下午
That afternoon,
我发现自己一直在想午餐男孩拍卖会的事
I found myself obsessing about the Basketboy auction.
我对布莱斯的感觉又不争气地死灰复燃了
I could feel myself backsliding about Bryce.
但雪莉喜欢他关我什么事
But why should I care if Sherry liked him?
我都不应该想起他
I shouldn't even be thinking about him.
我得赶快摆脱出来
I had to rise above this.
我得忘了布莱斯·洛斯奇
Bryce Loski was no longer in my life.
在那个拍卖会的早晨  我左右为难了
On the morning of the auction, I was on edge.
我发现自己不知不觉中
I found myself, without even knowing how it happened,
总盯着卖鸡蛋的存钱盒看
staring at my egg money.
我需要制定一个计划
I needed a strategy.
很简单
It was simple.
如果不带钱的话  我就不会胡思乱想了
If I left my money at home, I'd leave temptation with it.
但当我碰到斯杜比太太时  计划受挫了
My strategy suffered a setback when I ran into Mrs. Steuby.
朱莉安娜
Julianna.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, dear.
实在抱歉  我拖了这么长时间
I'm so sorry it's taken me so long to get this to you...
我今天一早上都没找到你
but I keep missing you in the morning.
斯杜比太太  我不想要这钱  算了吧
Mrs. Steuby, I don't want that. You don't have to...
不  别傻了  我怎么能白吃你的鸡蛋呢
No, don't be ridiculous. Of course I'm gonna pay you.
-我得付你钱  -我不想要  我不要
- I'm going to pay you. - I don't want that. I don't want it.
拿去给自己买点好看的衣服
Yeah, I want you to go out and buy yourself something festive.
买条七分裤怎样
Pedal pushers. Ha, ha.
-斯杜比太太  -再见  亲爱的
- Mrs. Steuby. - Bye, dear.
斯杜比太太  我不想要七分裤
Mrs. Steuby, I don't want pedal pushers.
不  你穿着会很好看的
No, no. You'll look great.
那好吧
It's okay.
没事  没什么大不了的  就当没有
It's okay. No big deal. Just pretend like I don't have it.
听说你要竞拍布莱斯
I hear you're planning to bid on Bryce.
什么啊  谁告诉你的  不是的
What? Who told you that? No, I'm not.
有人看到你今早拿着一沓钱
Someone saw you with a wad of cash this morning.
-你带了多少钱  -不关你的事
- How much do you have? - It's none of your business.
我今天不竞拍  我也已经不喜欢他了
And I'm not bidding, okay? I don't even like him anymore.
太阳真是从西边出来了
Oh, that'll be the day.
真的  去吧  在他身上浪费你的钱去吧
It's true. Go ahead, waste your money on him.
我不在乎
I don't care.
现在  请在场的梅菲德中学师生热烈欢迎
And now, will you all give a big Mayfield School welcome...
1963年度的"午餐男孩"们
to your 1963 Basketboys.
我嘴上说什么都不在乎了
I could say I didn't care all I wanted...
可当看到布莱斯西装笔挺地走上台
but seeing Bryce walk out in his jacket and tie...
手持野餐篮时
holding that picnic basket...
我的头脑又不清醒了
set my head spinning again.
十五美元第一次
Fifteen going once.
拍卖会似乎进行得飞快
The auction seemed to fly by.
十五美元第二次
Fifteen going twice.
梅茜·泰勒十五美元成功竞标
Sold to Macy Taylor for $15.
我还没回过神来  已经到艾迪·楚勒了
Before I knew it, Eddie Trulock was called.
8号是艾迪·楚勒
Number eight is Eddie Trulock.
也就是说下一个就是布莱斯了
Which meant Bryce was next.
艾迪是辩论队的成员
Eddie is a member of the debate team.
他的业余爱好有钓鱼
And his hobbies include fishing...
还有制作飞机模型
and model-airplane building.
有谁愿意出五美元
Who will give me $5?
-怎么没人竞标  他挺不错啊  -是啊
- Why isn't anyone bidding? He's so nice. - Exactly.
没人吗
Nobody?
八美元
Eight dollars.
八美元卖给朱莉·贝克啦
Sold to Juli Baker for $8.
怎么会这样呢
How did this happen?
是因为我同情艾迪吗
Was it because I felt bad for Eddie?
还是怕等下布莱斯登台时我管不住自己呢
Or was it because I couldn't trust myself with Bryce?
在去往多功能厅的路上
As I made my way to the multi-purpose room...
我回想着事情出人意料的变化
I contemplated the startling turn of events.
我就要和艾迪·楚勒共进午餐了
Here I was, about to have lunch with Eddie Trulock...
而那个曾让我朝思暮想的男孩
while the boy I mooned over for half my life...
竟然要和我的宿敌一起用餐
was going to share a meal with my mortal enemy.
谢谢你出价拍我
I wanna thank you for bidding on me.
那时候还真是惊险啊
It was touch-and-go there for a while.
不  是我想拍的  挺有意思的
No, I wanted to. This will be fun.
-听说你喜欢做飞机模型  -是的
- I hear you like building model airplanes. - Yeah.
我和我爸刚组装好一架米格19战斗机
My father and I just finished a Russian MiG-19.
是1955年生产的
It was made in 1955.
米格的第一款超音速战斗机
MiG's first supersonic fighter.
有点不好做  因为驾驶舱是凹进去的...
A little tricky because the cockpit was recessed...
与艾迪交谈时我努力想让注意力集中
I tried to give Eddie my full attention.
但这太困难了
But it was difficult,
因为布莱斯就在他后面
because Bryce was right behind him.
艾迪正说着进气阀什么的
Eddie was saying something about intake valves when...
突然  布莱斯起身径直向我走来
out of nowhere, bryce stood up and marched straight towards me.
朱莉  我得和你谈谈
Hey, Juli, I gotta talk to you.
你干什么啊
What are you doing?
他想要吻我  我的天啊
He was going to kiss me. To kiss me.
我长这么大就等着他的吻呢
All my life I've been waiting for that kiss.
但不是这样的吻  不是以这种方式
But not like this. Not this way.
我骑得飞快  到家时我觉得肺都要冒烟了
I pedaled home so hard, I thought my lungs would burst.
朱莉安娜
Julianna?
Julianna.
亲爱的
Honey?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不能
I can't.
宝贝
Sweetheart...
你可以跟我说说
you can tell me.
布莱斯想亲我来着
Bryce tried to kiss me.
是吗
He did?
在学校
In school.
在很多人面前
In front of everybody.
妈妈  别去开门
Mom, please don't get it.
可能是他
It's probably him.
宝贝
Sweetheart...
也许你应该跟他谈谈
maybe you should talk to him.
我不能
I can't.
布莱斯一点也不让我清净
Bryce wouldn't leave me alone.
他一直不停地给我打电话
He kept calling on the phone.
不断地敲门
And knocking on the door.
他甚至偷偷溜进院子  敲我的窗户
He even snuck around the house and tapped on my window.
朱莉  求求你  我得见你
Juli! Please, I gotta see you!
出来吧  就几分钟
Come on out, just for a minute!
他怎么就不明白  我就想一个人待会
Why didn't he understand that I just wanted to be left alone?
求求你了
Please!
两天之后  布莱斯不再烦我了
After two days, Bryce stopped.
我想这终于结束了
And I thought it was finally over.
直到有一天下午  我正要去客厅读书
Then, one afternoon, I was coming into the front room to read...
这时听到院子里有动静
when I heard a noise in the yard.
他干什么呢
Hey, what's he doing?
朱莉  冷静点  我允许他了
Juli, calm down. I gave him permission.
允许  允许什么了  他正在挖坑呢
Permission? Permission for what? He's digging a hole.
我跟他说可以
I told him he could.
可是为什么
But why?
我跟他说可以
I told him he could.
看他在我的草地上乱挖我很难受
It was torture seeing him dig up my grass.
爸爸怎么能让他这么做呢
How could my father let him do this?
布莱斯知道我在家里
Bryce knew I was there too.
他走了
He's gone.
一棵树
A tree?
他在种树吗
He's planting a tree?
那是不是...
Is it a?
我都不用问
I didn't really need to ask.
从树叶的形状
I could tell from the shape of the leaves...
和树干的纹理我就能知道
and the texture of the trunk.
那是一棵梧桐树
It was a sycamore tree.
当她走出那扇门时
When she walked out of the door,
我想起了第一次见到她的时候
I thought back to the first time I saw her.
怎么会有人想要躲避朱莉·贝克呢
How could anybody, ever, have wanted to run away from Juli Baker?
他用那双眼睛看着我
He looked at me with those eyes.
那双重又闪亮迷人的双眼
Those once again dazzling eyes.
我知道布莱斯·洛斯奇
And I knew that Bryce Loski
还在等待着我的初吻
was still walking around with my first kiss.
但是他不会等太久了
But he wouldn't be for long.
我们站在那里  我意识到这些年来
As we stood there, I realized that all these years...
我们从没真正交谈过
we never really talked.
需要帮忙吗
Do you need some help?
是的
Yeah.
但那一天  我们开始了
But that day, we started.
而且我知道我们要聊很久
And I knew we'd be talking for a long time.
BGM：Everly Brothers - Let It Be Me
♪ 感谢上天让我遇到你 ♪
♪ I blessed a day I found you ♪
♪ 我想和你一起厮守 ♪
♪ I want to stay around you ♪
♪ 不管天荒地老 ♪
♪ Now and forever ♪
♪ 让我爱着你 ♪
♪ Let it be me ♪
♪ 不要让我的梦想破灭 ♪
♪ Don't take this heaven from one. ♪
♪ 如果你真的需要温暖怀抱 ♪
♪ If you must cling to someone ♪
♪ 不管天荒地老 ♪
♪ Now and forever ♪
♪ 让我爱着你 ♪
♪ Let it be me ♪
♪ 当生命中出现爱 ♪
♪ Each time we meet love ♪
♪ 那一定是完整的爱 ♪
♪ I find complete love ♪
♪ 没有你的甜美笑容 ♪
♪ Without your sweet love ♪
♪ 我的生活将暗无天日 ♪
♪ oh, what would life be ♪
♪ 请不要离开我 ♪
♪ So never leave me lonely ♪
♪ 说你只爱我一人 ♪
♪ Say that you love me only ♪
♪ 并且你会永远 ♪
♪ And that you'll always ♪
♪ 让我爱着你 ♪
♪ Let it be me ♪
♪ 说你会永远 ♪
♪ Say you'll always ♪
♪ 让我爱着你 ♪
♪ Let it be me ♪